Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
Created time 16.05.03 16:33:40
请神父降福我 准我罪人告解 离我上次忏悔...
Bless me Father, for I have sinned. It's been...
已经有24小时了
24 hours since my last confession.
孩子  很晚啦
Son, it's so late.
没错 神父 我才刚(下班)...
Yeah, Father. Work has just...
我骗了康妮 就是我老婆
I lied to Connie. Uh, to my wife.
这很严重喔    - 我知道
- This is very serious. - I know.
我跟她保证要戒烟的
I promised her I quit smoking
她觉得抽烟不好  我已经很努力戒了...
She think's it's bad for me. And I'm trying, but...
但...我还是会偷偷塞了两根烟
Well, I snuck a couple of cigarettes.
还是三根
Maybe three.
是的
Yes.
这很难
It's hard.
是的
Yes.
但我还在戒
But I'm trying.
大清早五点 对某些人来说好梦正甜
It is 5.00 AM. Still shank of night for some.
但对曼尼斯来说 却是忙碌一天的开始
But, for Eddie Mannix, beginning of a new work day.
他的片场工作不断
The movie studio for which he works manufactures stories.
有白天的闹剧 也有晚上的爱情戏
Each, it's on daylit drama, or moonlit dream.
但曼尼斯可没有昼夜之分
But, the work of Essie Mannix cares not for day or night.
更无暇休息
And cares little for his rest.
就这样 小宝贝 开始搅奶油吧
That's right now. Churn that butter for me.
真棒
Atta girl.
天啊 你怎么来了?
Oh, Jesus Christ on a scooter. You, here?
葛罗莉的肖像权是公司的 法尔柯
The studio has the rights to Gloria's likeness, Falco.
底片给我就放过你
Give me the negatives and things will go easier on you.
这只是私人用途 艾迪
Easy. This is for private use, Eddie.
拜托
Come on.
天啊
Oh, boy.
就不能让女孩拍拍照片 高兴一下吗?
Can't a girl take a few pictures, have a few laughs?
天啊 艾迪 你还真古板
Cheez, Eddie. What a old sss-tick in the mud
听好了
Now, you listen to me.
你刚去了派对喝多了
You were at a party, you had too much to drink.
你也记不得是谁把你带来这
Somebody brought you here, you don't remember who.
快滚回家去
You're going home now,
你叫玛丽 乔 赛恩布洛特    - 好 艾迪
- you name is Mary Jo Schamroth. - Okay, Eddie.
艾迪喔 有人看到你外面的破车
So, Eddie Mannix, saw your heap outside.
打电话投诉制造噪音 扰民...
Got a call. Loud, disorderly...
搞不好还有性趴
Possible French postcard situation.
一定是有人恶作剧 玛莉刚去了化装舞会
Someone was pulling your leg. Mary Jo here was just at a costume party.
这可不是她的紧身裙
It's not really her dirndl.
她只想帮你们的退休金尽点微薄之力
She wants to contribute something to your pension fund.
不好意思让你们冒雨前来
Sorry to drag you out in the rain.
这个嘛  没关系啦
Well, say, no trouble at all.
你不就是那个葛罗莉吗??
Aren't you Gloria DeLamour?
不是 我名叫玛莉...姓那个 - 她姓赛恩布洛特
- No, no. I'm Mary Jo... something. - Schamroth.
对了  布莱恩
Say, Brian.
可以来根烟吗?
Can I bum a cigarette?
在古罗马时代
Ancient Rome.
马克西穆大帝统治提比略十二年后
12 years into the rule of Tiberius, ruler Maximus.
罗马军团称霸世界
Rome's legions are masters of the world,
从西部的伊比利亚半岛 到东部的亚历山大港的图书馆长廊
the stomp of it's sandals heard from the Iberian peninsula in the west
都可听到他们响彻云霄的步伐
through the halls of the great library of Alexandria in the east.
受压迫的人民 在罗马暴政下痛苦不堪
As oppressed people everywhere writhe under the Roman lash,
自由的人们和诸侯形成一致的信仰
freeman and vassal, are united in one compulsory worship.
奉凯萨大帝为世间众人的身体及灵魂之神
The emperor, Caesar, is Godhead, lord of every man's body and spirit.
不顺从统治的人
For those who will not submit,
将被送去远征 竞技场 甚至被钉十字架
the galleys, the arenas, even crucifixion await.
但从伯利恒尘土飞扬的街上
But there is a new wind, blowing from the east,
即将吹来一股新气息
from the dusty streets of Bethlehem, that
即将撼动凯萨帝国这座
will soon challenge the vast house of Caesar,
that edi铿ce wrought of brick and blood which now seems so secure!
用人民血泪砌成了看似稳固的大厦!
凯萨万岁! .
HAIL, CAESAR!
凯萨万岁! 之  耶稣的故事
HAIL, CAESAR! A TALE OF THE CHRIST
就在那 格拉古 多美啊!
There she is, Gracchus. And ah, what a beauty!
是啊 喔脱落糗死!  罗马!
Aye, Autolochus! Rome!
喝母狼奶长大 现反过来哺育她的儿子们
Suckled by a she-wolf and nurturing us, her sons in turn.
今晚我要去卡拉浴场洗澡
Tonight I bathe in Caracalla, and wash away
把我三百里法兰克路途的尘土洗掉!
the dust of three hundred miles of Frankish road!
向罗马前进!
To Rome. To Rome!
是的 向罗马前进! 凯萨政权的荣耀中心!
Yes, to Rome! Glorious center of Caesar's rule!
但在遥远的巴勒斯坦... 有个人在回家的路上
But far away, in Palestine. . . another man is coming home.
索尔 这个卑微的塔尔苏斯商人 即将被幻象吓到
Saul, humble merchant of Tarsus, is about to be struck down by a vision.
什么东东啊?
What thing is this?
葛洛莉已被送去圣母疗养院戒毒了
Gloria DeLamour has been checked into Our Lady of Perpetual Rest to dry out.
十点钟你要和葛雷利先生在华莱士会议室会面
You have a 10:00 a.m. with Monsignor O'Reilly at the Wallace Beery Conference Room.
跟他一起来的是天主教道德联盟的莱斯特
And he's bringing Lester Silkwood from the Legion of Catholic Decency
我们还要请了东正教弗拉索斯主教长
and we've also invited Patriarch Vlassos for the Eastern view.
他们看过剧本了吗?    - 好的
- Have they've read the script? - Roger.
再邀请一位犹太法学博士和新教教师 ...
Let's also invite a rabbi, and a Protestant padre of some sort
多听听各方意见    - 好的
- ... so we can get everybody's two cents. - Check.
How's production on Tucumcari"?
“图克姆卡里"(黄昏双镖客?)拍得怎样了?
主要部分按照进度 但第二组人员
Principal is on schedule but second unit has been idle
因为大雨关系在新墨西哥州闲晃四天了
in Gallup New Mexico for 4 days. Heavy rain.
气象预报怎么说?    - 不太乐观
- Forecast? - Not good.
Send an insert truck and have them shoot driving plates for Came the Rain.?
派辆货车去 让他们先拍“下雨罗”片段
- Check. - Jonah's Daughter?still behind?
好的    - “约拿的女儿”还是落后吗?
是的 导演说问题出在狄安娜 她的情况越来越糟
Yes, director says the problem is DeeAnna and she's getting worse.
我知道了 十点的会面完我会去看看
I know what it is. I'll drop in on her after my 10 o'clock.
好了 该打电话给纽约了
All right, let's call New York.
Mr. Schenk's of铿ce, line 2.
深刻先生办公室 二线电话
你好 多罗西 我是艾迪 老头来了吗?
Hi Dorothy, Eddie Mannix. The old man in?
嗨 曼尼斯先生 我看一下
Hi, Mr. Mannix, I'll check.
Natalie, I want the box of铿ce on The Debonaires?and on Blessed Event.?
娜塔莉 给我“彬彬有礼” 和 “喜事临门”的票房报告
顺便...是的  早安
Can you also... Yes. Good morning.
你好吗?    - 深刻先生 很好 谢谢
- How're you doing? - Mr. Schenk. Very well, thank you.
拍摄进度如何    - 正在拍...正在拍...
- Yeah. How's our productions. - Proceeding. . . Proceeding. . .
Merrily We Dance?starts shooing today.
“欢乐岁月”今天开拍
比尔得利给我们一部经典的剧本
Beardley Auberon gave us a draft that's extremely classy.
琼丹维克要演狄德莉 但还欠男主角
Joan Van Vechten is playing Dierdre, but we need a male lead
现在就要    - 杰克荷加斯可以吗?
- and we need him now. - Jack Hogarth available?
他没空 他在戒毒
No, Jack Hogarth is drying out at Cedars.
那盖博呢?    - 米高梅不肯借
- Well, what about Gable? - Metro won't lend us Gable
除非我们借他们科米斯基双胞胎
unless we give them the Kemsky Twins.
那可不行    - 当然不行 我也这么想
- Now, that ain't worth it. - Of course not, I agree.
那个小朋友霍比呢?
What about that kid, Hobie?
谁啊?   - 霍比道尔啊
- What? - Hobie Doyle.
霍比道尔?!你说真的吗?
Hobie Doyle?! Do you really think so?
到底他只是个跑龙套的!连话都不会...说!
After all he's-he's a dust actor! The man barely knows how to... talk!
但观众喜欢 不是吗?   - 是 当然 深刻先生
- But, people like him, right? - Yes, of course Mr. Schenk,
我同意 但霍比穿上...
I agree, but I don't know if Hobie Doyle, if he has the...
这个..这个..西装不知是啥样
the... the... poise in a dinner jacket.
我们需要一个演员 没错吧?    - 是的 真的很急
- We need an actor now, am I correct? - Yes, we do need someone pronto.
难道有更好的主意?    - 是没有 倒是真的
- You got a better idea? - No I don't. That's very true.
我先跟导演佛伦斯谈谈吧
Let me talk to Laurence Laurentz, the director.
应该可以
It could work. It could work.
挑霍比这主意不错
Hobie Doyle is a very promising idea.
白驹 !
Whitey !
卡!
And cut!
太棒了 霍比
Great, Hobie.
再来一次 我能把倒立的动作做得更流畅
I can do the handstand smoother if ya gimme another shot at her.
霍比 我们已经拍了四遍很棒的 马也够累了
We've got four good ones, Hobie, and Whitey is tired.
好吧 你说了算
Okay, you're the bossman.
如果可以吃午餐了 我要吃一盘豆子
If that's lunch I'm gonna grab me a plate a beans.
好了 各位 这是罗马!
All right kids, this is Rome!
当你们正在狂欢作乐时 安东尼那斯进来
You're over at this guy's house for a revel, and in comes Antoninus.
保持兴奋!
Lots of energy!
你在餐桌旁干嘛?!
What're you doing at the table of viands?!
你不是该捧着七弦琴吗!
- Huh? - You're supposed to be reclining, with the lyre!
抱歉    - 躺着捧着七弦琴!
- I... I'm sorry. - Recline with the lyre!
别拄着像座山 躺着
Don't sit on the pediment. Recline.
放轻松 欢乐点!    - 好啦
- Relaxed, festive! - Alright.
临时演员准备好没?   - 好了!
- Extras, set? - Set!
开始录影    - 我会盯着你
- Roll sound. - I got my eye on you.
开拍 喷泉!
Roll camera. Fountain!
凯萨万岁! 第十幕 第十遍
Hail, Caesar! 10A . Take 10.
开拍!
And action!
喔脱落糗死!
Autolochus!
听说你要回罗马!
I had heard rumors of your return to Rome!
不只是听说 尊贵的塞满地兔屎!
More than rumors, noble Sestimus!
我知道你是巴克柯斯的崇拜者
I see that you are the same worshiper of Bacchus.
真搞笑
What gaiety.
常言说得好
There is still truth in the adage,
What pleasures cannot be found in the villa of Sestimus Ainydias,
“在瑟斯提慕斯豪宅找不到的乐趣
cannot be found in Rome!?
在罗马更找不到!”
但言归正传 听说参议院又要派我们军团出征
But seriously, there is talk that the senate will send our legions out again
这次可不是去高卢
and this time not on a short march to Gaul.
这可是真的, 瑟斯提慕斯?
What truth to these mutterings, Sestimus?
参议院是在计划
The matter has been taken up in the Senate.
巴勒斯坦乱成一团
It seems that there is unrest in Palestine.
巴勒斯坦? 那可是与世隔绝的地方!
Palestine? That backwater!
他们可不会派第六军团去那个鸟不生蛋的地方吧!
They'll hardly be sending the Sixth Legion to that godforsaken patch of desert!
巴勒斯坦
Palestine.
- Ah hahaha... - Ha ha ha...
巴勒斯坦!
Palestine!
先别停
Holding for a dissolve,
继续笑
still laughing,
继续...卡
holding... and cut.
Fine, boys, that was just 铿ne.
很好 各位 很好
我表现可以吧?   - 停机!
- Was I alright? - It's a cut!
接着拍火炉场景
We'll move on to the brasier scene.
我刚刚如何
Was I alright with the mutterings,
我觉得有点...    - 没事 很好
- I felt a little... - Nah, it's fine.
换位 二十分钟后 火炉场景
Moving on. Brasier scene, 20 minutes.
赶到拖车那
Popping over to my trailer.
Okay, in the brasier scene, they changed passion?to ardor.?
好的 火炉那一幕 他们把“激情”改成“热情”
什么? 为啥? 我喜欢激情
What? Why? I like passion.
这才够厉害 激情!
It's strong. It's Passion!
这就是我在高卢待了三个月得到的问候?
Such is my greeting after three months' sojourn in Gaul?
不是这样的 乌苏丽娜
Not so, Ursulina,
我...我的热情...
my... my ardor...
我的热情就像...火炉里的余烬一样温暖
my ardor is yet as warm... as the embers of this brasier.
炉里的余烬...余烬
The embers of this brasier... brasier.
大家在等你 会拉客先生 - 不是这样的 乌苏莉娜
- They're ready for you, Mr. Whitlock. - Not so, Ursulina.
谢谢各位过来
Gentlemen, thank you all for coming
I know you have parishes, 铿ocks and temples making enormous demands on your time.
我知道你们有教区一堆事务要忙
但我很确定你们一定会很欣慰一般大众
But I'm sure you appreciate also that great masses of humanity
看这部电影时会得到更多的教育
look to pictures for information and uplift and,
和娱乐
yes, entertainment.
我们首都影业...
Now here at Capitol Pictures, as you know,
我们专业的人员 演员... 和顶尖的创意人正日以继夜的确保...
an army of technicians and actors and top-notch artistic people are working hard
把耶稣的故事搬上银幕
to bring to the screen the story of the Christ.
这是个了不起的故事 一个古老的故事
It's a swell story. A story told before, yes,
but we like to 铿atter ourselves that it's never been told
但我们想把它当作从未被人讲过的故事
投入如此大的制作成本和阵容
with this kind of distinction and panache.
或许你忘了圣经里讲过
Perhaps, sir, you forget its telling in the holy Bible.
Quite right, Patriarch. The Bible of course is terri铿c.
没错主教长 说到圣经 没错
但对千百万人来说
But, for millions of people,
他们会在电影里找到对照
pictures will be their reference point for the story, the story's embodiment;
找到故事的具体化形象 故事的...
The story's...
寓意    - 寓意
- Realization. - Realization.
You realize,?of course, that for we Jews,
当然了 对我们犹太人来说
任何神灵的具体化形象都是严格禁止的
any visual depiction of the Godhead is most strictly prohibited.
Oh.
但是 当然罗 对我们来说耶稣并不是上帝
But of course, for us, the man Jesus Nazarene is not God.
Ah-ha.
谁演耶稣?
Who plays Christ?
一个我们都很看好的年轻人 陶德何切伊瑟
A kid we're all very excited about, Todd Hocheiser,
我们找遍全国在俄亥俄州找到的
wonderful young actor we found in Akron, Ohio in a nationwide talent hunt.
陶德只是短暂露脸 保持高调
But Hocheiser is seen only fleetingly, and with extreme taste;
我们的故事是从罗马保民官
our story is told through the eyes of a Roman tribune,
Autolochus Antoninus, an ordinary man skeptical at 铿rst
喔脱落糗死的角度 一个普通人 最初半信半疑
but who comes to a grudging respect for this swell 铿gure from the East.
但后来勉强尊重这位东方神
演喔脱落糗死的是...
And Autolochus is played by. . .
败德会拉客
Baird Whitlock.
天啊
Oh my.
他还真有才华
Well, he is certainly a great talent.
"凯萨万岁!" 将会是部传世巨作 我们今年的大片
Now, "Hail, Caesar!" is a prestige picture; our biggest release of the year.
我们投入巨大成本
We are devoting huge resources to its production
in order to make it 铿rst-class in every respect.
以确保在各方面堪称一流
各位 鉴于巨大的投入 没有十足的把握这部片...
Gentlemen, given it's enormous expense we don't want to send it to market
不会冒犯任何美国人的信仰和信条之前
except in the certainty that it will not offend any reasonable American,
我们不会让它上映
regardless of faith or creed.
所以我们请各位来 你们看过剧本了
Now that's where you come in. You've read the script;
我想知道有没有因神学因素让这部片子夭折
I wanna know if the theological elements of the story are up to snuff.
我感觉战车大一段太假了
I thought the chariot scene was fakey.
怎么可能有人在全速前进的战车上跳来跳去?
How is he going to jump from one chariot to the other, going full speed?
这个嘛 我们可以再研究
Uh-huh, well, we can look at that.
但旧宗教方面而言呢...
But, as for the, religious aspect...
对耶稣的描述还算可以吧?
does the depiction of Christ Jesus cut the mustard?
耶稣的本质并非你们剧本
Well. The nature of the Christ is not quite as simple
... 写得那么简单    - 怎么说呢 神父?
- ... as your photoplay would have it. - How so, Father?
并非简简单单说耶稣是上帝 或者上帝就是耶稣
It is not the case simply that Christ is God, or God Christ.
说的对! 拿札勒人不是上帝!
You can say that again! The Nazarene was not God!
说他不是上帝不对   - 他只是凡人!
- He was not not-God. - He was a man!
不全是神    - 不对 先生!
- Part God. - No sir!
我们都有点神的气息 不是吗?
Rabbi, all of us have a little bit of God in us don't we?
这是我们信仰的精随
- Well... - It is the foundation of our belief
耶稣往往被当作上帝的儿子
that Christ is most properly referred to as the son of God.
上帝的儿子承担全世人的罪
It is the son of God who takes the sins of the world upon himself
这样其他上帝的子民像我们这些不完美的人
so that the rest of God's children, we imperfect beings,
透过信仰 才能到达天国
through faith, may enter the kingdom of heaven.
也就是说上帝是...分身?   - 说是 也不是
- So God is. . . split? - Yes. And no.
既分身 又合体    - 合而为一又分开
- There is unity in division. - And division in unity.
我有点听没有 主教长
I'm not sure I follow, Padre.
少年耶 你不懂 原因很简单
Young man, you don't follow for a very simple reason:
这些人脑袋有问题? 上帝有孩子吗?
these men are screwballs. God has children?
有养狗吗? 说不定还是条牧羊犬?
What, and a dog? A collie maybe?
上帝没有孩子
God doesn't have children.
他是单身汉 而且很生气
He's a bachelor. And very angry.
不对 他是生气过!   - 然后呢 气完罗?
- No, no. He used to be angry! - What, he got over it?
你信的是另一个时代的上帝!  - 缺乏爱!
- You worship the god of another age! - Who has no love!
不对! 他爱犹太人
Not true! He likes Jews.
上帝爱众人!    - 上帝就是爱
- God loves everyone! - God is love.
上帝就是上帝
God is who is.
这有啥奇怪的? 谁不是谁啊?
This is special? Who isn't who is?
但上帝为何要出现在电影里?
But how should god be rendered in a motion picture?
上帝才没出现在电影里!
God isn't in the motion picture!
那陶德演谁?
Then who's Todd Hocheiser?
各位 或许一时解答不了那么多问题
Gentlemen, maybe we're biting off more than we can chew.
我们先暂时搁置神的本质
We don't need to agree on the nature of the deity here:
我们先只看他表演 先不管他是谁...生的
if we can focus on the Christ, whatever his... parentage.
我要问的是: 我们对他的描述公正吗?
My question is: is our depiction fair?
还好啦
I've seen worse.
牧师?
Reverend?
不会冒犯到常人
There is nothing to offend a reasonable man.
神父?
Father?
剧本写得虔诚恭敬 品味独特 格调高雅
The motion picture teleplay was respectful and exhibited tastefulness and class.
你几时变成专家了?
Who made you an expert all of a sudden?
那拉比 你怎么看呢?
And, What do you think, Rabbi?
不予置评
Eh. I haven't an opinion.
怎么样呢?   - 我不...不错 怎么了?
How'd we do? - I don't... fine. What's up?
Can't 铿nd Baird Whitlock.
败德会拉客不见了
他离开剧组有一小时了
He left the set over an hour ago,
说要回他化妆室 但不在那
said he was going to his dressing room but he isn't there.
嗑药去了? 大白天的? 我疯了不成
Out on a bender? Middle of the day? Am I crazy.
你没疯 但就是不在
You're not crazy, but no.
我还找过酒吧 餐厅 摩铁 一个影子都没
I checked the Til Two, Dan Tana's, Rusty Scupper. Not a soul.
还是回家了? 打给他老婆没?    - 打了
- Home, maybe? Called his Wife? - Yep.
萝拉怎么说?
What'd Laura say?
他不在 他从没回家过 他就是个混蛋 问他小三去
He's not home, he's never home, he's a louse, try one of his chippies.
打给那个叫法兰奇的女场记了吗?   - 打了
- Called that script girl, what's her name, Francine? - Check.
剧组有哪个女人不见了吗?    - 没
- Any of the gals missing from the set? - Nope.
好 才消失一小时?  先别紧张
Alright, gone an hour? We won't worry yet.
霍比?
Hobie?
公司说这里没你的事了 要你回摄影棚报到
The Studio says you're finished here and you're to report back to the Lot.
干嘛?    - 要让你变身
- How come? - They're changing your image.
Okay
Okay.
公司还说今晚你要护送卡洛塔去首映会
And the Studio says  you're escorting Carlotta Valdez to your premier tonight.
干嘛? 我又不认识她
How come? I don't know her.
公司安排的 你身分不同了
Studio's arranging it, they're changing your image.
去他的!
Damn it!
夫人 你又胀气了吗(肚子更大了)?
You have gas again, ma'am?
夫人? 叫我小姐! 我像结婚了吗?
Ma'am? Miss! Do I look married?
不像 小姐   - 不! 没错 又胀气了
- No, miss. - No! Yeah, gas again.
问他吧 他知 好啦 一边去吧
Ask him, he knows. Alright, scram.
狄安娜 还好吗?
How are you, DeeAnna?
我好吗? 湿答答的
How am I? Wet.
I don't think I'm going to 铿t in that fish-ass after this week.
再过一星期 我就塞不进那该死的鱼尾巴了
过明天 水上芭蕾组的人就可以当你替身了
Well, we should have the water ballet in the can after tomorrow;
到夜总会那一幕会给你穿宽松的
in the nightclub scene, wardrobe'll have a gown for you that's more forgetting.
有想嫁谁了吗(肚子又搞大了)?
Any more thoughts about who you might marry?
我不在完那一套了 都结两次了
I ain't doing that again. I had 2 marriages,
都还得靠公司花钱摆平
and it just cost the studio a lot of money to bust them up.
Well, we had to have those annulled, one was to a minor mob 铿gure .
我们不得不解决那两段婚姻 一个混黑社会的
文森不是黑社会的!
Vince was not minor!
巴迪呢 是个吸毒的乐队主唱
And, Buddy Flynn was a bandleader with a long history of narcotic use.
我就说嘛 两个都是混蛋
Yes, and that's what I'm saying, they were both louses.
在嫁第三个混蛋对我没好处
Marrying a third louse ain't gonna do me no good.
我们不是给你介绍几个不错人选
We've offered you some very suitable, clean young men.
不是小白脸 就是软脚虾 娘娘腔 !
Pretty boys. Saps and swishes!
难道有可靠的好男人我会放过吗?
What? You think if there wasn't a good reliable man I wouldn't have grabbed him?
那嗯嗯啊啊呢? 他是孩子的爹吧?
What about Arne Seslum? He is the father, isn't he?
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
婚姻不一定要天长地久 但迪安娜
Marriage doesn't have to last forever. But, DeeAnna,
生出没爹的孩子 会给我们声誉带来麻烦
having a child without a father would present a public relations problem for the studio.
拍水上芭蕾对我们形象大有好处...
The aquatic pictures do very nicely for us...
So you go and strap on the 铿sh-ass and marry Arne Seslum.
那你去穿鱼尾巴啊嫁给嗯嗯啊啊好了
拍水上芭蕾不只对我们 对你都有好处
The pictures do well for all of us. And it's a tribute to you:
观众爱你 因为他们知道你有多"无辜"
the public loves you because they know how innocent you are.
那倒是
That's true.
我去看看嗯嗯啊啊要不要娶你 你确定他是孩子的爹吗?
Let me see if Arne is open to matrimony. You're sure he's the father?
是啊 我肯定是 非常
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Absolutely. He's the father, yes.
算相当确定吧
Pretty sure.
喂 马西 把我的鱼尾巴拿来!
Hey, Maxie, bring me my ass back!
嘿 嘿 伙计 过来
Hey, hey. Buddy, come here.
首都影业公司
CAPITOL PICTURES STUDIOS
你好啊 霍比?    - 你好啊 死蚵弟
- How ya doing, Hobie? - Hello there, Scotty.
他们让你来摄影棚拍戏啊?
They got you shooting on the lot?
曼尼斯把我从西部片场调回来 说要让我演部歌舞剧
Well, Mr. Mannix, pulled me off the Western, says I'm doing a movie on a sound stage.
还弄了间专属化妆室说
They built a drawing room.
他来了 罗伦兹先生
He's here, Mr. Laurentz.
Ah.
亲爱的 欢迎 我是罗伦斯罗伦兹
My dear boy, welcome. Laurence Laurentz.
你看起来很棒喔 感觉怎样?
And you look wonderful, wonderful, how do you feel?
这个嘛...领口有点给我紧 (本来就不是给你穿的)
Well, this here collar... collar is a little tight.
No no, no, it's nicely 铿t, looks a marvel, just takes a little getting used to.
不会不会 很合身 待会就习惯了
霍比 现在我们要拍的就是这里
Now, Hobie. Here is our set.
没错
And, in fact, that's right, yes.
待会你就从那进场 从大厅门看到比夫的手提箱
You enter from there, having just seen Biff's valise in the foyer,
虽然啊莱格声称他没来过
in spite of Allegra's claim that he hasn't been to the house.
我超崇拜啊莱格    - 应该是的
- I'm sweet on Allegra. - Indeed you are.
但我看到了比夫的手提箱    - 应该是的
- But I've seen Biff's grip. - Indeed you have.
And so here we 铿nd you...
就在此时...
Hobie, we 铿nd you haunted by unspoken suspicions.
霍比 你要表现出被猜疑所困
被比夫的手把想困扰
Haunted. By Biffs grip.
是他的手提箱 是的 但 但
By his valise, yes, but, but,
这位是狄德莉
here is Dierdre,
她对你有好感 感觉机会来了
harboring deep feelings for you, and sensing opportunity.
狄德莉     - 是狄德莉
- Dierdre. - Dierdre, yes.
她开始跟你勾勾狄 一起坐在沙发上开始讲话
So at her importuning, you join her on the couch, and conversation ensues.
她会跟我勾勾狄吗 罗伦斯先生?    - 是罗伦兹
- So, she's-she's gonna importune, Mr. Laurence? - Laurentz.
喔 不好意思 她打算跟我来一段吗 罗伦兹先生?
Oh, I'm sorry. She's gonna importune, Mr. Laurentz?
我是不是该注意一下?
Is that something I should be concerned about?
她只会叫你过去和她坐一下 也就是过去然后开始讲话(不会吃了你)
She'll simply ask you to join her on the couch,
is all I mean to say, and conversation ensues.
好的 了解
Okay, I gotcha.
很好  我们先过一次如何?
Very good, very good, let's try one shall we?
好的 我试试    - 很好 太棒了
- Sure, I'll give her a go. - Wonderful. Splendid.
我得提醒一下...
The only thing I would suggest is...
before your 铿rst line, you respond to her line with a mirthless chuckle.
你说第一句台词前 先低声笑一下
低声笑一下
A mirthless chuckle.
是的 是因为你对啊莱格莫名的猜疑
Yes, I think given your unspoken suspicions about Allegra,
低声笑一下
- A mirthless chuckle. - Uh-huh.
好的罗伦斯先生 我会试试   - 是罗伦兹
- Okay, Mr. Laurence, I'll give it a shot. - Laurentz.
喔 抱歉罗伦兹先生 我会试试
Oh, gosh, I'm so sorry, Mr. Laurentz. I'll give it a shot.
MERRILY WE DANCE? 27A, Take 1
“欢乐岁月”第27幕 第一遍
开拍
Action.
喔 盲弟 过来沙发跟我坐
Oh, Monty. Come join me on the divan.
看来啊莱格不来了 真无聊啊
It seems Allegra's a no show; which is simply a bore.
但 我可以陪你打桥牌
But, I'll partner you in bridge.
你干嘛摆臭脸?
Why the pout?
要是这么简单就好啦
Would that it were so simple.
卡
And cut.
停机
That's a cut.
很好 太棒了
Very good. Wonderful in fact.
这次我们得做点小小改变
But let's try it a little differently this time.
好的    - 不如这样...
- Sure. - Let's try.
Well, let's see, 铿rst of all why don't we dispense with the mirthless chuckle.
这样吧 先别低声笑了
别低声笑    - 不 省省吧
- No mirthless chuckle. - No, no need, really.
哪个猪头想的 是我指导无方 我错在想太多了
It was a bad idea, bad directorial, my fault, over thinking the thing.
既然你这样说了 我很乐意再试一次 低声笑
Well if you say so, but I'm happy to do another,
maybe try her one more time.
如果你要我低声笑 我一定办得到
I mean if you want that chuckle I sure wanna give her to ya.
不用了 到这地步就省省吧
No no no, completely unnecessary under the circumstances,
观众应该会了解你的心声
I think the audience can to that extent they can read your thoughts,
他们会感觉到你的悲伤
and they, they will assume your mirthlessness.
好的 你说了算 罗伦斯先生    - 是罗伦兹
- Okay, you're the bossman, Mr. Laurence. - Laurentz.
喔 天啊 抱歉 罗伦兹先生
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry, Mr. Laurentz.
还有  这遍呢 试着看着狄德莉说话
Also, this time, let's try, actually looking at Dierdre as we speak,
看着她的眼睛 略带悲伤说出台词
looking into her eyes, and speaking our line with a certain... ruefulness.
悲伤喔 好的    - 这不难 明白吧?
- Ruefulness, okay. - Yes. Because it's not so simple, you see.
不像她提议的那么简单
- Not so simple as she suggest. - Okay.
知道吧...感情可没那么简单
And... Your feelings are not so simple.
知道 先生
No, sir. Okay.
开机
Roll camera.
MERRILY WE DANCE? 27A, Take 2
“欢乐岁月”第27幕 第二遍
开拍
Action.
喔 盲弟 过来沙发跟我坐
Oh, Monty. Come join me on the divan.
看来啊莱格不来了 真无聊啊
It seems Allegra's a no show; which is simply a bore.
但 我可以陪你打桥牌 你干嘛摆臭脸?
But, I'll partner you in bridge. Why the pout?
要是这么简单就好啦
Would that? It were so simple.
ㄎ....ㄚ...卡
Cu... Cut.
太好了 太好了
Very good. Very good. Umm.
过来
Come. Come.
好吧  不如这样
All right, let's try this,
你的台词 像我这样说
your line, just say it as I say it,
你按照我说的方式说你的台词
say your line exactly as I'm about to.
照我这样说   - 好的
- Just as I'm about to do. - Sure, okay.
要是这么简单就好啦
Would that it'were so simple.
Would that it'wuuuhs so simple.
要是这么简单就好啦 - 要是这么简单就好啦
- Would that it'were so simple. - Would that it'wuuuhs so simple.
My dear boy, why do you say that? Why do you say, twuuuuuh?
孩子啊 你干嘛那样说? 怎会这样 “ㄏ....”?
是你说要照你那样说阿   - 没错  但...
- Well, you said, say it like I say it. - Yes, but...
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦
Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple.
要是这么简单就好啦 - 要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦
- Would that it'were so simple. - Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple.
要是这么... 要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦
Would that it... Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple.
不对 看我的嘴
No, no. Watch my mouth.
要是这么简单就好啦 要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦
- Would that it'were so simple. - Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple.
头别动  要是这么简单就好啦
Keep your head still. Would that it'were so simple.
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦 - 要是这么简单就好啦
- Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple. - Would that it'were so simple.
要是...我还要尝试  罗伦兹先生
Would... I'm trying to say that, Mr. Laurentz.
是罗伦斯
Laurence. Mm.
我还以为...刚刚是罗伦兹说
I thought... a minute ago it was Laurentz.
那好 我们就叫名字好了 叫我罗伦斯好了
No. We can use Christian names, my good dear boy, Laurence is fine.
就像我叫你霍比?
- Just as I call you Hobie? - Okay.
要是这么简单就好啦
So. Would that it'were so simple.
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”   - 把手放下
- Would that it twuu... - Put your hand down.
Would that it'were so simple.? Trippingly.
“要是这么简单就好啦”轻快点
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦 轻快点
Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple. Trippingly.
没要你说轻快点 把台词念轻快点
Don't say trippingly. Say the line trippingly.
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....” 要是...要是...
Would that it twuuuuuuh... Would... Would...
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦 - 要是这么简单就好啦
- Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple. - Would that it'were so simple.
带悲伤 悲伤
Rueful, rueful, rueful. Hmm.
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦 - 要是这么简单就好啦
- Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple. - Would that it'were so simple.
要是...   - 简单悲伤
- Would... - Rueful, simple.
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....” - 带点悲伤
- Would that it twuuu... - Sorrowful simple.
充满悲伤 你应该充满感情 悲伤的说
You can say sorrowful. Rueful. Sorrowful.
要是这么简单就好啦 - 要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”
- Would that it'were so simple. - Would that it tw...
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....” - 怎么会? 怎么会这样?
- Would that it twuuuuuuh, - Why? Why are you doing this?
要是这么简单就“ㄏ....”好啦 - 别乱动
- Would that it twuuuuuuh, so simple. - Keep still.
停拍?! 要停多久? 你怎么跟导演说的?
Stall?! For how long? What do I tell the director?
我们还在努力找他 我不希望被狗仔知道
That we're looking for him. But we don't want it in the gossip columns.
Baird on a bender or in a love nest or wherever we end up 铿nding him.
败德不是在花天酒地 就是在爱巢 最终我们还是会找到
只要跟片场有关就不能停
As far as the set is concerned it's business as usual.
Tell the A.D. Baird is out brie铿y with a high ankle sprain.
就跟助理导演说败德脚扭伤了暂停拍摄
好 但没他怎么拍?
Fine, but what do we shoot without him?
我们下午才弄好火炉说
We got the brasier scene up this afternoon.
可不可以先排没他的戏? 用他的替身查克
Could you get through it shooting around him? Maybe use his stunt double, Chunk Mulligan.
查克不会演戏
Chunk can't act.
让编剧把他台词删掉一些
Get the writer to trim his speeches.
Well maybe, but then what do we do? All we got left is the 铿nal scene.
然后怎么办?我们还有最后一幕没拍
喔脱落糗死要在忏悔的小偷脚边讲话
Autolochus's speech at the feet of the penitent thief.
那可是整部戏的高潮啊!
It's the emotional climax of the entire picture!
我们要看到喔脱落糗死受到耶稣的感召!
We got to see Autolochus has absorbed the message of the Christ!
我可以明白    - 我们需要败德的明星魅力
- Yeah, I can see that. - We need Baird's star power, his charisma.
没错 他的情感... - 真挚感情!发自肺腑 整部戏的精随
Sure, his emotional...
This can't be faked! It's the heart and soul of the picture!
我了解    - 然后电影结束
- I understand. - End of the film,
我们可不能随便让一个...
we can't just give that speech to some...
某个...罗马蠢蛋
some... Roman schmoe.
不 不 不 是 是 是 我了解
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got it.
但他的狂欢还有一两天
But his benders can last a day or two.
停拍损失大吗?    - 太大了
- What does it cost to shut down? - Plenty.
可知这部戏阵容多大 可占用五跟十四号影棚
You know how big the picture is, we're on Stages 5 and 14,
如果演到最后一幕
if we're carrying everybody in the final scene
who's up on cruci铿xes that's 340 an hour hardship pay, 8 hour minimum.
一个小时要付340美元薪水 每天至少八小时
是 是   - 再加上 还失去...
- Yeah. Yeah. - Plus, we lose...
曼尼斯先生 对不起    - 现在没空
- Mr. Mannix, I'm sorry. - Not now.
... 这周末跟福斯公司签约的陶德
... we lose Todd Hocheiser to Fox at the end of the week.
我们本该签下来 谁知
Shoulda made him exclusive; who knew.
对不起 先生...    - 现在没空!
- Sorry, sir. It's... - Not now!
是罗伦兹先生啦 我拦不住!
It's Mr. Laurentz, I can't stop him!
曼尼斯 这样我没法搞!   - 不可以 不可以
- Mannix, I won't have it! - No, no.
For two decades the words Laurence Laurentz presents"
二十年来 我这"罗伦兹"名号
可是对观众意义重大!   - 没事了 娜塔莉
- has meant something to the public! - It's alright, Natalie.
好 瓦特有什么再跟我说
Okay, Walt, let me know.
说说你的想法..罗伦斯?
What's on your mind, uh... Laurence?
霍比不会演戏!
Hobie Doyle cannot act!
霍巴特道尔是电影巨星
Hobart Doyle is one of the biggest movie stars in the world.
仅限于骑马! 但这是剧情片 曼尼斯
On horseback! But this is a drama, Mannix.
真正的戏剧!还加上百老汇元素
A real drama, it's an adaptation of a Broadway smash!
需要受过训练的专业演员 而不是会马术的小丑
It requires the skills of a trained thespian, not a rodeo clown.
请你让兰特来演!
I begged you for Lunt!
曼尼斯 很抱歉 但我得提醒你...
Mr. Mannix, I'm sorry, but, you wanted me to make sure
不要错过皇家花园饭店的午餐 你还没跟我说要约谁
you didn't miss your lunch at the Imperial Gardens.
你一直没跟我说
You never told me who with.
疯啦 谁会想看到兰特
Nuts. Look, no one wants to see Lunt.
演员不再换了 这是深刻先生的决定
We're not recasting, this came from Mr. Schenk himself,
就是用霍比 这孩子有兴趣吗?
it's Hobie Doyle. Is the boy game?
喔 他可有兴趣了 还外行的很!
Oh, he's game. And gamey!
如果他需要帮忙 你则无旁贷
Well, if he need help, it's your job to help him.
我会去跟霍比谈谈 看看你们拍的片子
I'll have a talk with Hobie and take a look at what you've shot,
现在呢 我得赶去跟人吃午餐
but right now, I've got a lunch.
瑟斯提慕斯你说得很对
What truth to these mutterings, Sestimus.
别吵 恩格斯
Quiet, Engels.
真高兴见到你 曼尼斯先生 你的桌子在那
How pleasant to see you, Mr. Mannix, your table is right over here.
谢谢你 亚瑟
Thank you, Arthur.
你好吗 曼尼斯?    - 卡达西先生 你好
- How ya doing, Mannix? - Mr. Cuddahy.
他们调的鸡尾酒不错喝 这地方我喜欢
They mix a hell of a Mai Tai. I like this place.
抱歉让你久等 这是个艰难的抉择
Sorry to keep you hanging, it's a tough decision.
先别道歉 我们有一星期时间考虑
Nothing to apologize for, we said the deal was on the table for a week.
来吧
Go ahead.
不 我正在戒烟
Nah, I'm... I'm trying to quit.
我想看看能帮上什么忙
I just wanted to visit again to see if
或者对我们建议还有什么不清楚的?
there was some impediment we could help with,
or if something in the offer isn't clear?
没有 很清楚 你们的建议很大方
The offer's very clear. And very generous.
我们想让你能欣然接受
We want to make it easy for you to say yes.
是这样 曼尼斯 我们需要一位 像你这样有才华的人来解决问题
Look Mannix, we need a guy with your talents in management, problem-solving.
你得好好为将来打算
And you need to think about the future.
洛克希德公司发展很快
Lockheed is booming.
现在大家都坐飞机了 我们即将进军喷射客机市场
Everyone is riding in airplanes, and we're moving into jet airplanes.
新时代来了 曼尼斯 我们要当新时代的人
It's a new age, Mannix, and we're part of it;
你现在所待的产业有啥未来可言?
the industry you're in, what's the future there?
大家有电视看了谁还去看电影?
What happens when everybody owns a television set?
还有人每个周末去看电影吗?
Will they still be going to pictures every week?
我们认为是家庭...    - 我不是要说风凉话
- Well, we like to think that family... - I don't mean to denigrate.
电影业真的很有趣
I'm sure the picture business is pretty damned interesting.
但也无足轻重 不是吗?
But it's also pretty frivolous, isn't it?
航空业才是举足轻重的行业和人
Aviation is serious; serious business, serious people.
You won't be babysitting a lot of oddballs and mis铿ts,
不需伺候那些怪咖
应付那么多棘手的难题
shouldering a lot of crackpot problems.
是有些人不好伺候 但...
We have some kooks, sure, but...
当然是些怪咖 都是装出来的
Of course they're kooks, it's all make-believe.
我还跟自己说别贬低你的行业说
I told myself I wasn't gonna badmouth the competition, and look at me.
不好意思 曼尼斯 来谈正事
Sorry, Mannix, I'll stick to what we're about.
给你看个东西
Let me show you something.
听过比基尼环礁吗?    - 没
- Ever heard of the Bikini atoll? - No.
A test site, just a couple of rocks in the middle of the Paci铿c
这是我们的试验场 几星期前
还只是太平洋中央的几块石头
until a few weeks ago.
直到我们用上真家伙
When we blew the Aitch erino.
或许我不该这么说
Shouldn't be telling you this.
这才是真实的世界
It's the real world.
氢弹
Hydrogen bomb.
核融合装置
Fusion device.
末日大决战    - 当时就有洛克希德 正进行...
- Armageddon. - And Lockheed was there. We had a...
曼尼斯先生 有您的电话
Call for you, Mr. Mannix.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂    - 兜不拢先生收到绑架的电报
- Hello. - Mr. Dubrow has a telegram on a kidnapping.
刚收到吗?    - 是的 要他拿去给你吗?
- He has it now? - Yes, he does. Shall he bring it to you?
不用 叫他等我 我去找他
No, have him stay on the set, I'll go to him.
好 再见
Okay, good bye.
不好意思 卡达西 有急事
Sorry, Cuddahy, work emergency.
不管怎样 我还会在那工作
Still do work there, for the day anyway.
你的话很有说服力 我想好跟你说
You make a good case. I'll let you know.
你是好莱坞来的吗?
You one of the Hollywood people?
是吧
Maybe.
他们在里面
They're in there.
请进! 大家都欢迎你!
Please! Enter! All are welcome!
Ah!
那些东西很讨厌
Those things are a nuisance.
谢谢
Thank you.
待会要吃三明治
We'll have sandwiches in a minute.
喝茶吗?    - 茶?
- Tea? - Tea?
好啊
Uh. Okay. Yeah.
那 这...    - 怎么回事吗?
- And, uh... - And what's going on?
是啊    - 我们刚读完会议纪录
- Yeah. - Well, we've just read the minutes
汤姆打算展开一个新业务
and Tom was about to bring up new business.
我没听到会议纪录
I missed the minutes.
这没关系    - 不过是无聊的过程
- I wouldn't worry about it. - They're usually pretty boring.
这开的是什么会啊?
What kind of a meeting is this?
Well it's not a meeting,? so much as a, a...
其实也不是什么“会”不过是个...
就是个...学术研究
It's a... more of a, a study group.
你们研究啥?
And you're studying?
所有愉快的事
Oh, all sorts of jolly stuff.
历史啊    - 经济啊
- History. - Economics.
不都一样对吧? 历史 经济?
Same thing, isn't it? History, economics?
你不觉得吗?
Don't you agree?
这个...嘛...我也没...
Well. . . I'm. . . I'm not really
念过历史
a student of history.
别吵 恩格斯
Quiet, Engels.
谢谢...人性已经分离了?
So...  Thank you. ... man is split?
是人的功能分离了
Well, man's functions are split.
那是小人物 一般老百姓为谋生而工作
There's the little guy, the regular Joe, who works for a living.
他是肉体...是寄主
He's the body, uh. . body politic.
大脑才是老板 主人...
Then there's the brain, the boss, the owner...
大脑不是老板!   - 不对! 寄生虫才是老板!
- The boss is not the brain! - No, no! The boss is parasite!
老板的确不工作 但有他的功能
Well it's true that the boss doesn't work, but he has a function.
他控制...
He controls the means of...
生产 但那不是功能 那是...
...production, sure, but that's not a function, that's...
寄生主义! 在肉体里!    - 闭嘴!
- Parasitism! On the body! - Shut up!
存在一般人体!是...
On the body politic! Of the regular Joe! It's...
人是一个整体 一个简单的经济体
Man is oddity, a simple economic agent.
人的基藤互为分离 互相矛盾 必须协调才能克服
Man's institutions are split, expressing contradictions that must be worked through.
他们以互为因果
And they are worked through
又可预见的方式协调配合 历史就是科学
in a causative, predictable way: history is science.
这正是辩证法的精随
This is the essence of the dialectic.
知道吗 如果你懂经济的话
You see, if you understand economics,
就能把未来事都写下来
you can actually write down what will happen in the future,
with as much con铿dence as you write down the history of the past.
就像写昨天的历史一样自信
因为这是科学 不是迷信
Because it's science. It's not make believe.
我们不相信圣诞老人
We don't believe in Santa Claus.
Another 铿nger sandwich?
还要三明治吗?
谢谢 如果理解没错的话...
Oh... thank you. But if I follow this correctly...
这是哪位?
Who's that guy?
帮我们拍照的史密特罗维基先生
Mr. Smitrovich takes pictures for our newsletter.
我们对历史的理解
Our understanding of the true workings of history,
让我们从中获得权力的杠杆
give us access to the levers of power.
例如说你的摄影棚纯粹就是资本主义运作的工具
Your studio, for instance, is a pure instrument of capitalism.
正因如此 它又揭露了资本主义的矛盾
As such it expresses the contradictions of capitalism,
and can be enlisted to 铿nance its own destruction.
最终导致自身的灭亡
多令人激动啊!
Which is exciting!
这可能对一般老百姓很有帮助
It can be made to help the little guy, the regular Joe.
是肉体!    - 闭嘴!
- The body politic! - Shut up!
虽然目的就是要剥削一般老百姓
Even though it's purpose is to exploit the little guy.
还有肉体    - 你是支持一般老百姓的
- And the body politic. - You are for the little guy.
支持反对都不重要
For the little guy, against, it doesn't matter,
历史还是原来样子 我们知道它会是什么样
history will be what it will be, and we already know what it will be,
但 没错 我们支持一般老百姓    - 你不是吗?
- but, yes, we're for the little guy. - Aren't you?
闭嘴!    - 开玩笑吧?
- Shut up! - Are you joking?
我 支持一般老百姓? 我当然支持一般老百姓!
Me, for the little guy? Of course I'm for the little guy!
他是喜剧演员吗?
Is this guy a comedian?
听着 我还是回去吧 摄影棚一定失序了
Listen. I better get back, the studio's got to be going nuts.
能不能今天先告一段落 下次继续?
Can we cut it off now and pick it up right here at the next study session?
好 知道吗
Okay, well, See.
恐怕事情没那么简单
I'm afraid it's not that simple.
就这样 败德会拉客终于明白自己被共产党抓来了
And so Baird Whitlock found himself in the hands of Communists.
与此同时 离马里布浪花很远的地方
Meanwhile, far from the crashing surf of Malibu,
艾迪离开与洛克希德公司代表的午餐
Eddie Mannix, torn from his lunch with the Lockheed man.
赶回浩大的电影公司
hurries back to the vastness of Capitol Pictures,
那里永不疲倦的机器不停的运转
whose tireless machinery clanks on,
为世上虚弱的人们制作今年的梦想配额
producing this year's ration of dreams for all the weary peoples of the world.
Hey, numbskull, didn't you see the Rolling?light was on.
猪头 你没看到"拍摄中"的灯号吗
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Mannix. Can I help you 铿nd someone?
喔 抱歉 曼尼斯先生你找谁?
不用
No.
喔脱落糗死    - 怎么了?
- Autolochus. - Yeah?
你为何穿着简陋出现在我的房间?
Why do you present yourself in my chambers in such humble fashion?
别看我 乌苏莉娜
Do not look upon me, Ursulina.
The 铿res of the brasier of Sestimus have latterly burned my face!
瑟斯提慕斯火炉熊熊火焰烧毁了我的脸!
虽然阿基米德的药膏能让我快速复原
Though the unguents of Arkimideus promise shortly to undo the damage.
喔脱落糗死 你知道我爱的是你的心
Autolochus, you knew that my love is for you,
不是你的外表
not for your station.
我对你的热情... .
And my ardor for you is yet as warm as the embersh of thish bras...
灰烬...对不起 知道吗 对不起 (明星在我们手上 准备十万 听候指示)
this... this ember... I'm sorry, I'm sorry. You know, I'm sorry.
"我们就是未来"
"We are the future."
什么意思?    - 我哪知
- What does that mean? - Beats me.
早上不知谁把这张纸塞进我门缝
Somebody slipped it under my door some time after we broke this morning.
跟谁提起吗?    - 没
- You mention it to anyone? - Nope.
好 我们先别露声色
Okay, Walt, let's keep it that way.
对了 还有 查克演得不错
Hey, by the way. Chunk sounded good in there.
艾迪 曼尼斯 制片总监
EDWARD MANNIX HEAD OF PHYSICAL PRODUCTION
娜塔莉 可以帮我接会计部的史图吗?
Natalie, could you please get me Stu Schwartz, Accounting?
史图在二线
Stu Schwartz on two.
史图 你好吗?    - 好啊 艾迪
- Stu, how are you? - Good, Eddie.
我要小额现金
- I need some petty cash. - Okay.
十万    - 十万?
- A hundred thousand. - A hundred thousand?
- I'm sorry, did I say petty? - You did.
抱歉 我有说“小额”?    - 有说
说来话长 以后再跟你说
Well, it's a long story and I'll tell it to you sometime.
- You have that much in the of铿ce? - Yeah.
那里有那么多吗?    - 有
要多大箱子装?
How much space will that take up?
曼尼斯先生    - 好的 应该可以
- Mr. Mannix. - Okay, this might do it.
朵拉来了 问你有没有空?
Uh. Thora Thacker just came in, wonders if you have a moment?
朵拉啊
Thora Thacker.
跟她说我电话中 我从阳台走
Tell her I'm stuck on a call. I'll leave through the patio.
没讲多久嘛
Call didn't take so long, then.
是啊 不是 我直说吧 有事吗 朵拉?
Yes... no. Fast talkers. What can I do for you, Thora?
那我也直说 只是出于礼貌通知你一声
Well, I'll be fast too. I only wanted to notify you as a courtesy
我要刊登败德会拉客的事
that I'm running my very Whitlock story.
是喔?什么故事?
Yeah? What's the story?
就那事啊 我有可靠来源 我想让它见报
The story. I have a credible source and I'm going to run it,
你知道我说的是啥事
and I think you know what story I mean.
我哪知 败德会有什么事
I have no idea. There's nothing going on With Baird.
有的话我怎会不知道?    - 艾迪别装了
- I would know, wouldn't I? - Don't play dumb, Eddie.
我说的是...
I'm talking about...
On Wings as Eagles.?
“长翅如鹰”的事
虾米?    - 明天上报
- What? - Running it tomorrow.
首先
First of all.
首先 那事没有看点
First of all, there's nothing to that story.
I've heard it, it's been around forever, and it's never been con铿rmed.
剧本我看过了 大家都看过了 没人要
再来 你不可能刊登
And secondly, you can't print that.
就算可以 你也不会灯
Even if you could print it, you couldn't print it.
你不会 你没那么低劣
And you wouldn't want to. Thora, it's beneath you.
我就是那么低劣
The facts are never beneath me.
大家不想看到事实 只想盲从
People don't want the facts, they want to believe.
我们产业就是那样 我的你的都是一样
That's our great industry, mine and yours too.
大家相信败德会拉客是大明星 是个好人
They want to believe that Baird Whitlock is a great star, and a good man.
你承认他不是    - 不 我说他是
- You're admitting he isn't. - No. I'm saying he is,
虽然内容空洞 也没料可暴
though it's beside the point. There's nothing to it, nothing to the gossip.
我又不是狗仔!    - 不 不 不 当然不是
- I AM NOT A GOSSIP COLUMNIST! - No, no, no. Of course not.
别把我跟我妹混为一谈!
Don't confuse me with my sister!
不会啦...
Hardly. But look...
明天你一定要登吗?   - 我一整篇专栏
- Do you have to run it tomorrow? - It's my entire column.
我想跟败德谈谈 只能安排下午了
I'm happy to talk to Baird for comment, but it'll have to be this afternoon.
败德现不在 改天吧
Baird is unavailable right now. Wait one day.
朵拉 就等一天 明天我给你的专栏一个真实故事
Thora, wait one day and I'll give you a true story for tomorrow's column.
是关于...霍比的故事
A little something... about Hobie Doyle.
我的读者才不鸟霍比 他只会骑马
My readers don't care about Hobie Doyle. He wears chaps.
读者喜欢卡洛塔吗? 两人关系暧昧
Do they care about Carlotta Valdez? They're sweet on each other.
你真得看看他们 形影不离
You should see the two of them together, like peas in a pod.
想用这个换掉关乎我事业的故事?
Trade the story of my career for a puff piece on Hobie Doyle?
不干   - 不是交换
- I don't think so. - You're not trading anything,
只要你等一天 就能得到一个多年的故事
you're waiting one day on a story that's years old.
等一天 你就可以访问败德 让你明白你的故事多乏味
Wait one day, I can let you talk to Baird and show you your story's the bunk,
如果我说错了 也不影响你写的专栏
and if I'm wrong no skin off your nose, you run the column.
同时 你还得到一个独家新闻 没人知道霍比跟卡洛塔的事
In the meantime you have an exclusive, no one else knows about Hobie and Carlotta.
说好了 就酱
No kidding. You're it.
到底朵拉是什么样的名字啊?
What kind of name is Thora, anyway?
这是一千九百万读者信赖的名字
It's a name that 19 million readers trust.
别耍他们
Don't play games with them, Eddie.
喔 没人要耍
Oh, no body's playing games here.
这够大吗?
Is that big enough?
哈罗 艾迪 出于礼貌通知你一声 明天我就要让故事上报
Hello Eddie, I'm notifying you as a courtesy before I run tomorrow's story.
特色莉 我刚才见过你的...算了
Thessaly, I just saw your... never mind.
你好吗? 什么故事?  - 败德的故事
- How're you doing? What's the story? - It's about Baird Whitlock.
相信我 那是老掉牙的事了 没啥好登的!
There is absolutely no truth to that old story, believe me!
老掉牙?   - 老掉牙 毫无新意
- Old ? - Old. Stale. Rotten.
我说的是今天的事
I'm talking about today.
什么?
What?
有小道消息说他今天从片场消失了
A little bird told me that he disappeared from the set today.
喔 那个喔 不 不 是的 他该休息一下了
Oh! That. No, no, yes, he did have to take a break.
受了点小伤 脚扭到了    - 你以为我在说啥?
- Minor injury, high ankle sprain. - What did you think I meant?
没什么 我刚见到你姊了
No, nothing. I saw your sister earlier,
她想重刊以前的八卦
she was trying to resurrect some old gossip about Baird.
喔 她就是这样 这老女人
Oh, I'm sure she was. That cow.
对什么都后知后觉
She wouldn't know a news story if it bit her on the posterior.
是啊 她就是...    - 脚扭到了?
- Yeah. Well, she's... - High ankle sprain?
你就只会编这种藉口?
Is that really the best you could come up with?
谁不知他的花边故事
We all know about the womanizing
还有酗酒的故事
and the drinking jags and the trips to San Berdoo.
败德是个好人 只是脚扭到了
Baird is a good family man. He has a high ankle sprain.
曼尼斯先生!
Mr. Mannix!
- What's up, Peanut? - Natalie told me to 铿nd you PDQ.
怎么啦 小花生?   - 娜塔莉要我尽快找到你
我知道这听来诡异 她说有人从未来打电话来
I know it sounds screwy, but she said someone's calling from the Future.
未来...天啊!特色莉 我得赶回去
The futh... Good lord. Thessaly, I have to run.
如果知道败德在哪 让我访问他
If you do know where Baird is, you must let me talk to him.
当然 我马上就会知道他在哪 特色莉 一定...
Sure, I'll find out where he is, right away, Thessaly, and I'm sure...
特色莉是什么样名字啊?
Say, what kind of name is Thessaly, anyway?
这是两千万读者信赖的名字 他们要真相 艾迪
It's a name that 20 million readers trust. They want the truth, Eddie.
真相  是喔
The Truth. Yes.
会给他们真相的
We're going to give it to them.
在三线 霍比在里面    - 好
- On 3. And Hobie Doyle is in there. - Right.
曼尼斯先生你好    - 谢谢你过来
- Hello, Mr. Mannix. - Thanks for coming, Hobie.
等一下
One second.
哈罗 曼尼斯...
Hello, Mannix...
可恶
Damn.
挂了 娜塔莉 再打来马上跟我说
Hung up, Natalie. Tell me the second they call back.
是
Yes, sir.
怎么回事 曼尼斯先生? 你好像在等什么
What's going on there, Mr. Mannix? Looks like you're expecting rain.
没...什么
Nah, it's... nothing.
How's the 铿rst day on the picture? Getting comfortable?
第一天拍得怎样?还适应吗?
喔 我觉得还不错
Oh, I guess it's going pretty good,
那个 ...罗伦兹先生
that Mr. uh... Laurentz,
真是个大好人 一直在教我
he's an awful good man, he's helping me get through it,
所有功劳都要归他 毕竟我还是个新人
I give him all the credit in the world, me the new hand in the bunkhouse,
让我说好多台词 这得...
they got me talking a lot which takes a little...
花时间适应 对着摄影机说话我还蛮喜欢的
getting use to,  talking with the camera looking at me but heck I enjoy.
好 很好
Oh, good, that's fine.
Usually on a picture I just say Whitey!?or Whoa, there,?
以前在片里只跟马说"白驹!"或"喂 等等"
但在这终于可以
but, this-here it's talking,
and it's people listening, that threw me little at 铿rst
第一次跟人说话 还真不习惯
但我渐渐习惯了
but I think I got my leg up onner now.
That's 铿ne. Laurence came in this morning to tell me how well you're doing.
罗伦兹早上还夸赞你的表现不错呢
继续听他的话
You just continue to do whatever he says.
他知道怎么拍好电影
He knows how to make a quality picture.
的确 他的要求是尽善尽美
That is true, he will not quit on a take until it has quality.
打来了吗?
Is that them?
抱歉 先生 不是 曼尼斯太太在一线要接吗?
Sorry sir, no, do you want Mrs. Mannix on 1?
嗨 亲爱的
- Hi, hon. - Hi.
你知道的啊 我就是忙
Oh, you know, busy.
Uh-huh.
I thought he asked to play in铿eld.
我以为他要守野说
知道了
I see.
也许该让他知道要信守诺言
Well maybe we should make him honor that commitment.
没错  你是对的
That's true. Of course you're right.
好 我会打给教练
Okay. Okay, I'll call the coach.
我爱你
- Sure. - Love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
曼尼斯先生要不要我给你弄个大点箱子?
Mr. Mannix, you want me to run out and get you a bigger grip?
这个好像小了点
That one looks a little bit snug.
霍比
Hobie.
这箱里有十万美金
There's a hundred thousand dollars in that attache case.
赎金
Ransom money.
败德被绑了
Baird Whitlock has been kidnapped.
这下糟了
This is bad.
对各地的明星都不是好消息
Bad for movie stars everywhere.
你不知谁干的?
And you got no idea who's mixed up in this thing?
我觉得是临时演员干的    - 为何是临时演员?
- I would look at the extries. - The extras. Why?
那是因为没人了解他们
Well, you just never know about an extrie.
来来去去的 没个例外 我就在片场
They come and go. Every one else, I'm on the set,
I see the guy setting the 5K I think, Why, there's old Bud, setting the 5K.?
巴德忙着装灯
场记 道具人员也都忙着
Script girl, wrangler, same thang.
临时演员就不同了
Extries, that's different.
连帮个小忙都不用 我是说 临时演员有好有坏
Not making a blanket call here, I mean, there's good extries and bad extries.
我意思是
All I'm saying.
你看着临时演员
You look at an extrie,
看不出他倒底在想啥
you got no idea what he's thinking.
又打来了 二线
He's back, line 2.
喂    - 钱好了吗?
- Hello. - Do you have the money?
好了     - 八号影棚
- Yes, I have it. - Stage 8.
八号影棚?    - 配电箱后
- Stage 8. - Behind the electrical box.
配电箱后
Behind the electrical box.
就放在那?    - 对
- Just leave it there? - Right.
哪时放败德?    - 拿到钱再说
- When do I get Baird? - When we have the money.
我马上去
I'll do it right now.
可以借你的腰带吗?
Can I use your belt?
晃船
SWINGIN' DINGHY
'晃船'要打烊了 各位
The 'SWINGIN' DINGHY' is closing, folks.
我要收拾了 你们也该离开了
Time for me to clean up. Time for you to clear out.
小伙子们 再见了 八个月后见
So long, fellas. See you in 8 months.
再见了 小帅哥们
- See you later. - Later, boys.
八个月?
8 months?
没错 明早就要启航了
Yeah, we're shipping out in the morning.
天啊!八个月看不到女人
Golly! 8 months without a dame.
谁受得了?    - 受不了也得受
- Can you beat it? - You gonna have to beat it.
?We are heading out to sea ?
我们即将启航 ? We are heading out to sea ?
?and however it will be, ?
不管如何 ? and however it will be, ?
?it ain't gonna be the same. ?
一切都不一样了 ? it ain't gonna be the same. ?
?cause no matter what we see, ?
因为不管看到什么 ? cause no matter what we see, ?
?when we're out there on the sea, ?
在汪洋大海中 ? when we're out there on the sea, ?
?we ain't gonna see a dame. ?
都看不到女人 ? we ain't gonna see a dame. ?
?we'll be searching high and low ?
那就四处找寻 ? we'll be searching high and low ?
?on the deck and down below ?
甲板上下到处找 ? on the deck and down below ?
?but it's a crying shame. ?
实在很无奈 ? but it's a crying shame. ?
?Oh, we'll see a lot of fish ?
只会看到很多鱼 ? Oh, we'll see a lot of fish ?
?but we'll never clock a dish. ?
但我们对鱼没性趣 ? but we'll never clock a dish. ?
?We ain't gonna see a dame. ?
看不到女人 ? We ain't gonna see a dame. ?
?No dames! ?
没女人 ? No dames! ?
?we might see some octopuses ?
或许可看到章鱼 ? we might see some octopuses ?
?No dames! ?
没女人 ? No dames! ?
?or a half a dozen clams ?
或几只蛤 ? or a half a dozen clams ?
?No dames! ?
没女人 ? No dames! ?
?we might even see a mermaid ?
或许有美人鱼 ? we might even see a mermaid ?
?But mermaids got no gams! ?
但对美人鱼没性趣 ? But mermaids got no gams! ?
?No gams! ?
无趣 ? No gams! ?
嘿 下来
Hey, get off of there.
快点
Hey, come one.
嘿!快点
Hey! Come on.
嘿!
Hey!
喔 拜托 天啊
Oh, come on. Oh, Christ.
喔 拜托!
Oh, come on!
?Have I got a girl for you. ?
帮你找个女人 ? Have I got a girl for you. ?
?out there on the sea! ?
在汪洋大海中 ? out there on the sea! ?
?Here's how it will be ?
我们就这样 ? Here's how it will be ?
?I'm gonna dance with you, pal ?
一起来跳舞 ? I'm gonna dance with you, pal ?
?you're gonna dance with me! ?
你我一起欢乐共舞 ? you're gonna dance with me! ?
?When we're out there on the sea ?
在汪洋大海中 ? When we're out there on the sea ?
?we'll be happy as can be ?
尽情欢乐 ? we'll be happy as can be ?
?Or so the Captain claims! ?
舰长就是这么说 ? Or so the Captain claims! ?
?But we have to disagree. ?
恕难苟同 ? But we have to disagree. ?
?Cause the only guarantee ?
唯一有趣的就是 ? Cause the only guarantee ?
?Is I'll see a lot of you ?
你们有我相伴 ? Is I'll see a lot of you ?
?And you'll see a lot of me! ?
我有你们相伴 ? And you'll see a lot of me! ?
?And it's absolutely certain ? ?That we'll see a lot of sea. ?
我们绝对有大海相伴 ? And it's absolutely certain ? ? That we'll see a lot of sea. ?
?But we ain't gonna see  ? ?no dames. ?
但就是没女人 ? But we ain't gonna see  ? ? no dames. ?
?No dames!  ? ?We're going to sea! ?
没女人 有大海 ? No dames!  ? ? We're going to sea! ?
?We ain't gonna see ?
只有大海 ? We ain't gonna see ?
?No... ?
没... ? No... ?
酒吧还在营业!
This place looks open!
怎么回事...
What the...
你 出去
You, out.
停下来
- Stop. - Hey!
快停下来 这里可不是玩的
Cut that out. This ain't that kind of a place.
卡!
Cut!
很好    - 很好  各位 归位
- Ah, okay. - Okay, kids, back to one.
Okay.
过来 伯特 再来一次
Come here, Burt Gurney. We go again.
有什么要改吗 瑟斯伦先生?
Anything different, Mr. Seslum?
对 对 对  不  不 都很好 但这次...
Yah, yah, yah, No, no, no. Mostly pretty good, but this time...
别把抹布放酒保头上
Don't put dish rag on bartender's head.
你可是大明星 伯特 谁鸟酒保啊
You're a big star, Burt Gurney. Who cares about the bartender.
你才是明星
You are the star.
我的脚色就是这样 脾气好   - 瑟斯伦先生 我不介意他...
- That's my whole character, this little bird. - Mr. Seslum, I don't mind if he...
就酱    - 你好啊 伯特
- It is decided. - Hello, Burt.
你好 曼尼斯先生
Hello, Mr. Mannix.
啊恩特
- Arne. - Hello.
听着 我可不想管闲事
Listen, I don't want to stick my nose in other people's business,
但我知道...你跟迪安娜交往过?
but, uh, I understand you've been... associating with DeeAnna Moran?
没错  我们交往过
- Yah, yah. We associated. - Yes.
但现在没了 别担心 艾迪
But no more. No more. Don't you worry, Eddie Mannix.
但 啊恩特 你知道她的...
But Arne, you are aware that she's...
我们说好不一起拍片的
This must not be in movie magazines, that we associated.
当然不会上八卦    - 不能让我老婆看到
- No, no, of course not. - My wife cannot read this.
你的...什么?
Your...excuse me?
Ilsa P铿ug.
就伊尔莎啊
- Ils... - Ilsa P铿ug Seslum.
伊尔...    - 伊尔莎
他在马莫
In Malmo.
我还不知道    - 都两个小孩了
- I was not aware of that. - Yah, two children.
现在还怀第三个
Well, a third on the way, apparently.
你喜欢运动吗 艾迪? 滑雪吗?
Do you enjoy physical culture, Eddie Mannix? Do you ski?
不 我从没真正滑雪过 看来很有趣
No, I, uh, never took it up. Seems like a lot of fun.
我没再跟迪安娜扯了  来抱抱
I no more associate with DeeAnna Moran. I hug you.
拜啦
Good bye.
我在那里过夜
I spent the night.
我感觉有人在插我 然后我醒来
So I feel somebody poking at me and I wake up
看到是克拉克 他说
and it's Clark. And he says,
"你的钥匙不在那 看来我们得用走的"
"Well, your keys aren't in there, so I guess we're walking."
那时盖博还没出名呢
This was back before Gable was Gable.
我们常在周末去圣伯多
We used to go to San Berdoo every weekend,
鲍勃有时也来 那时兰动还在营业
Bob Stack would come up sometimes, the Blue Grotto was still open.
大伟那时是个开公车的
Dave Chasen was a busboy.
这地方不错喔!你的吗?
Quite a place! Yours?
当然不是
Oh, gracious no.
我们一个成员的 今天下午刚好没来
It belongs to a member of our study group. He couldn't be here this afternoon
没看到你会难过的
He'll be sad to have missed you.
他是你的粉丝    - 太好了
- He's a fan. - Uh-huh. That's swell.
我昏过去了 在这醒来
So, I black out, I wake up here
跟自己说
and I say to myself,
败德 你不能再干这种傻事了
Baird, you got to stop doing this,
但你却说我算是被绑来的
but you're saying, actually, technically I was kidnapped.
这个么...技术上是的
Well... technically, yes.
- And there's gonna be a ransom. - I'd hardly call it a ransom.?
会有赎金吗    - 我不太想说成"赎金"
Benedict there, that's Benedict de Bonaventure, he wrote The House of Ahasuaris.?
这位是班尼特 "雅哈随卤之家"的作者 超轰动的一部片
帮电影公司赚了大把钞票
Enormous hit. Made the studio millions of dollars.
班 你有分到吗?
Did you see any of those millions of dollars, Ben?
没
I did not.
Dutch over there, Dutch Zweistrong wrote All The Way To Uruguay?
那位是道奇 "直到乌拉圭"的作者
I wrote all the All The Way?pictures.
一系列"直到乌拉圭"剧本都是我写的
All successful. You see any of the pro铿ts, Dutch?
都很轰动 你有分到利润吗?
这里都是些编剧
- HA! - All of us here are writers.
电影都是来自我们的巧思妙想
The pictures originated with us, they're our ideas,
但版权却为电影公司所有
but they're owned by the studio.
我不是说只有编剧被剥削 你看看自己 败德
I'm not saying only writers are being exploited, I mean, look at yourself, Baird.
知道吗  公司对我还不薄
Oh, you know, the studio takes pretty good care of me.
你是啥  小朋友吗?
What're you, a child?
I think what Herschel's trying to say is?
我想贺歇尔的意思是
虽然电影公司拥有拍片的方法
just because the studio owns the means of production,
但凭什么就能拿走所有的钱...我们的钱
Why should it be able to take the money... our money,
我们辛劳创造的价值 让他们随随便便就打发掉?
the value created by our labor, and dole out what it pleases?
That's not right. So, no. No, I wouldn't call it ransom.?
这哪对啊 所以呢  这应该不叫"赎金"
叫补偿   - 没错.
- Payback. - That's right.
直到最近我们研究小组呢 开始努力一件事
Now, until quite recently our study group had a narrow focus.
我们要全力在剧本中加入共产主义的元素
We concentrated on getting communist content into motion pictures.
当然 做得神不知鬼不觉
Always in a sub Rosa way, of course.
做得还很成功
And we've been pretty darn successful.
You remember, in Kerner's Corner? the Town Hall scene,
还记得"科纳的角落"里 市政府那一幕
市议员逆转选举 让嘉斯当上市长?
where the aldermen overturn the rotten election and make Gus the mayor?
没错
Yeah.
我想我们转变了一些人的思想
I like to think we've changed a few minds.
可是...
But, then. Well.
来自史丹佛的马丘斯博士加入我们
Then Dr. Marcuse came down from Stanford, joined the study group.
教我们直接采取行动
And started teaching us about direct action.
实践   - 行动
- Praxis. - Action.
我们每个人...都在追求自己的经济利益
We each pursue our own economic interest,
我们不能超越历史的规律
we ourselves are not above the laws of history.
但在凭藉能力追求利益的同时
But in pursuing our interest with vigor,
我们却加速了对立
we accelerate the dialectic,
加速人类历史的终结并创造了新人类
and hasten the end of history and the creation of the New Man.
此外 还赚到了钱    - 闭嘴!
- Plus, we make a little dough. - Shut up !
我们讲的不是钱 是经济
We're not even talking about money, we're talking about economics.
是喔
Sure. Good.
说得好
Good stuff.
那...这样说来...我能分到赎金吗?
So... now, do I get a... share of the ransom?
不
Well,
会拉客先生  被绑人基本上是分不到赎金的
no, Mr. Whitlock. You could hardly share in your own ransom.
那很不道德
That would be unethical.
各位 我觉得那很不公平!
Well, it doesn't seem fair, fellas!
我是说 这场戏若没我的配合哪成
I mean, the whole set-up only works if I play along, right,
若我不说谁绑了我?
if I don't let on that I know who kidnapped me?
没错啊
Yes, that's right.
如果我说出名字呢?
What if I named names?
如果...我...说出真相呢?
Mmm. If I... Just I... tell the truth?
我想你不会 会拉客先生
I don't think you'll do that, Mr. Whitlock.
如果我们说出...
What if we told the truth about...
On Wings as Eagles?
"长翅如鹰"的真相呢?
希德
Sid.
得帮迪安娜想想办法
we have to work something out for DeeAnna Moran.
她又嫁了吗?    - 不是 她有了
- She get married again? - No, that's the problem.
未婚生子    - 不好办
- Having a child, not married. - Tough.
是喔 还没爹呢
Yeah. No father.
当然某处有个爹...
Well, of course there is one, somewhere. . .
但天知道    - 对啊...所以呢可否 ...
- But who knows. - Exactly. So, is there any way,
只是个提议
I'm just spitballing here,
她是否可以领养自己的孩子?
any way she could adopt her own child?
有趣喔    - 单亲...
- Interesting. - As a single...
让她消失一阵 再回来
- She disappears for a while, reappears. - Uh-huh.
跟大家分享领养孩子的喜悦
And she wants to share her blessings, adopt a child.
可以..她一直渴望做妈妈
Sure, she's always... yearned to be a mother.
就是这样    - 我觉得有何不可
- That's it. - Well I don't see why not.
加州法律没禁止父母领养自己的孩子
Nothing in California statute prohibits adoption by one's own parent.
这可是创举 严格来讲 她必须
This is new ground. Technically, she'd have to
先把孩子送给第三者
give up the baby to a third party.
乔苏丽文    - 乔苏丽文 没错
- Joe Silverman. - Joe Silverman. Exactly.
让他当几天养父
He's the foster father, for a few days.
再把孩子还给她
She hands the kid to Joe, he hands it back.
我来研究一下    - 好的
- I'll do some research. - Alright.
曼尼斯先生 五点半了   - 真令人兴奋
- Mr. Mannix, it's 5:30. - This is exciting.
...问过所有副导演了
... and asked all the assistant directors.
其中一个说有个临时演员
One of them said that an extra
在瑟斯提慕斯院子里鬼鬼祟祟的
in the courtyard of Sestimus-Aniydias scene seemed jumpy.
好 把那个临时演员的名字跟瓦特说 让瓦特逼他
All right, get Walt the name of the extra so he can bring him in and sweat him.
跟他说 如果说出败德在哪
Walt should tell him we won't press charges
就不告他    - 明白
- if he tells us where Baird's been taken. - Check.
如果他装傻 或那副导搞错了
If he plays dumb, or if the A.D.'s wrong and he is dumb,
...再找其他临时演员    - 明白
- ...check the other extras - Check.
特色莉打来说你答应她今天采访败德
Thessaly Thacker called, said you promised her an interview with Baird today.
更正一下 是朵拉   - 不 那是特色莉
- Check that, it was Thora Thacker. - No, it was Thessaly.
跟她说 他去看医生了
Tell her, he was at the doctor longer than expected,
明早在片场可以见到他
she can see him on the set bright and early tomorrow.
明白 最后这句是真的吗?   - 最好是
- Check. And is that last part true? - Let's hope so.
这倒提醒了我: 给我"长翅如鹰"全部还在职的名单
That reminds me: I need a list of everyone
who worked on On Wings as Eagles? who's still at the studio.
On Wings as Eagles? that's a while ago, now.
"长翅如鹰"有段时间了
除了败德跟导演 谁会有
Aside from Baird and the director it won't be a long list.
好 把名单给我...还有事吗?    - 有
- Yeah, get it for me. That it? - No.
还有一件:有位卡希达先生来电 说你认识他
One more thing: a Mr. Cuddahy called, said you know him.
是 是    - 说有要事见你
- Yeah yeah. - Said it's urgent he see you one last time.
建议你今晚七点在老地方见
Suggested same place, seven this evening.
为什么? 别管了 好吧 跟他说我会去
Why? Never mind. Okay, tell him I'll be there.
去你家?
- Back to your place? - Oh...
你好啊 CC    - 我想我们还是...
- Hello, CC. - I rather thought we might go to...
嗨 艾迪
Oh, hi, Eddie.
Wanna lace up what you got on Merrily We Dance?
可以看看"欢乐岁月"吗?
正在做 我要配些音乐
It's up now. I'll put some music on it.
罗伦斯 罗伦兹导演
Laurence Laurentz presents
欢乐岁月
Merrily We Dance
计程车!
Taxi!
去你家?    - 多无聊
- Back to your place? - Oh, what a bore.
去昂那戴嘉湖度周末吧
I rather thought we might go to Lake Onega for the weekend.
就我们俩
Just the two of us.
我没带行李 留在你家玄关了
I don't have my valise I left it in your foyer.
没换衣服不会死啦     - 没事
- Oh, you'll get by without a change. - Suits me.
只要你不介意从你自己的派对上溜走 啊莱格
If you don't mind skipping out on your own party, Allegra.
没事    - 还要从盲弟身边溜走
- Suits me. - And skipping out on Monty.
也没事
That suits me as well.
喔 可怜的盲弟
Oh, poor Monty.
盲弟可不知道...     - 那就不会伤到盲弟
- What Monty doesn't know. - Won't hurt Monty.
喔 盲弟 过来沙发跟我坐
Oh, Monty. Come join me on the divan.
看来啊莱格不来了 真是无聊阿
It seems Allegra's a no show, which is simply a bore.
但 我可以...
But, I'll...
快按倒带...
Reverse...
快按倒带
Reverse. Reverse.
我不该戴围巾的
I shouldn't wear scarves.
看来阿格莱不来了 真是无聊阿
It seems Allegra's a no show, which is simply a bore.
但我可以陪你打桥牌
But, I'll partner you in bridge.
你干嘛摆臭脸?
Why the pout?
这可是...
It's...
很复杂的
complicated.
真高兴又看到你 曼尼斯先生
How pleasant to see you again, Mr. Mannix.
多谢你又回来 曼尼斯    - 还好
- Thanks for coming back, Mannix. - Sure.
你可把我们逼得豁出去了 不是吗?
You're taking us down to the wire, aren't you?
这可不是耍技俩 这是重大抉择
It's not a ploy. It's a big decision.
当然!没关系
Absolutely! No foul.
今天下午没能说服你 董事会很在意
But the board was concerned when I couldn't give them a yes this afternoon,
所以授权我呢
so, they've authorized me to say this.
只要你在十年合同上签字
You sign on, your term of contract is 10 years.
没错 你知道的 对吧?
Yeah. You get it, right?
就是说你拿到股票选择权
That means your stock options are guaranteed to vest.
如果你在合约期满后退休你就不用再工作了
You'd never have to work again, if you chose to retire after your term.
考虑一下
Think about it.
这可是终身职位
Life time employment.
You wouldn't be a glorified working stiff like you are now.不用像现在帮人打工
You wouldn't be a glorified working stiff like you are now.
你将经营一个事业 而非一个马戏团
You'll be running a business, not a circus.
喝点什么?
Drink?
烟呢?
Cigarette?
不了   我得走了
No, no. I got to run.
我得跟我老婆谈谈
I should talk this over with my wife.
当然 该跟家人谈谈
Of course, talk it over, think about your family,
明早跟我说
let us know in the morning.
Oh!
就当这是贿赂
If you think this is a bribe, you're absolutely right.
你有两小孩吧 一男一女?
You have two kids, right, a boy and a girl?
没错
That's right.
他们会喜欢的 他们以前喜欢火车
They love this stuff. Used to be trains.
你好阿 霍比
Hello, Hobie.
喔 你好 卡洛塔
Oh, hello, Carlotta.
我迟到了吗?     - 不 没关系
- Am I late? - Oh no, it ain't nothing.
谢谢你和我忆起拍戏
Thanks an awful bunch for coming to this picture with me,
不知你喜不喜欢家畜 但我喜欢
I don't know if you like livestock but I think it's got moments
我真的喜欢...你真漂亮
I really do. You look very pretty
谢谢 霍比
Well, thank you, Hobie.
我一定会喜欢这部片子 你的片子我都喜欢
I'm sure I'll like the picture I like all of your pictures.
我也喜欢你的 都很神奇
Well, I like yours too, they are just the craziest things
头上顶着香蕉跳舞不容易吧?
Is it hard to dance with all them bananas on your head?
没啥  谁都会
Oh, no. Anyone can do it.
主要靠下半身 嘴唇 眼睛和大腿
It's all in the hips and the lips and the eyes and the thighs.
小艾迪要我跟你提提他的棒球赛
Little Eddie wanted me to tell you about his baseball game.
他们赢了
They won.
太棒了
That's terrific.
我忘了打给教练 艾迪是游击手吗?
I should've never called the coach! Eddie played at shortstop?
他打得很好 他想留在那
Mm, and he did so well, he wants to stay there now.
太好了  问题解决了
Great, it took care of itself.
达琳的西班牙语考试考得很好
And Darlene did very well on her Spanish test.
太好了 她一直在担心说
That's good, she was worried about that.
谢谢你帮我煮的热饭 亲爱的
Thanks for heating up the roast, hon.
要热牛奶吗?   - 不了 谢谢 我要咖啡
- Warm glass of milk? - No, thanks, hon. Coffee.
我要赶回片场 有要事要处理
I gotta run back to the studio, a few things to take care of.
天阿 又要加班啦
Gee, another late night.
Mm.
知道吗  洛克希的开出更好的条件
You know. . . Lockheed improved their offer.
薪水高 也不会像现在那么忙
Darned good money. And the hours wouldn't be crazy like this, either.
有人要你是好事
It's nice to be wanted.
那当然  但...
Yeah, sure, but...
你怎么想? 他们要我明天回覆
what do you think? They wanna know tomorrow.
我喜欢工作时间短点
I like the shorter hours.
可是你怎么想 亲爱的? 你自己清楚
But what do you think, honey? You know best.
戒烟戒的怎么样了啊?
How's it going with the smoking, dear?
你知道啊...
Oh, you know...
洛杉矶的人们不是已经开始夜生活或入睡了
The denizens of Los Angeles make ready for nightlife, or for sleep.
但艾迪两者都没
But Eddie Mannix will have neither.
即便是在马里布海滩 太阳也已下山
Even in westerly Malibu the sun has moved on,
徒留辽阔而不知疲倦的大海 盲目地拍打海岸
leaving the vast and tireless sea to heave itself blindly upon the shore.
共产党们正享受少有的优闲
The communists welcome a rare moment of leisure.
抗争中短暂的休息
A brief surcease from struggle.
败德会拉客成了他们的信徒 追随他们的信念
Baird Whitlock has become their acolyte, a convert to their cause,
他的信念强烈而非勉强
his belief compelled but not grudging.
他渴望从博士那学到更多
He now seeks to learn more from professor Marcuse
好全力投入这项事业
and becomes ever more committed to the quest
促成人类历史终结 早日再创新人类
to hasten an end to history and bring on the New Man.
这正是我要说的
That's exactly what I was talking about
我和丹尼在雷诺发生的事
that's what happened to me when I went to Reno with Danny Kaye
他要我帮他替背上的毛!
and he asked me to shave his back!
同样的事! 我在想 谁会从中获利?
Exact same thing! Because I'm thinking, who benefits?
另外 大家都认为丹尼是个混蛋
Also, I got to tell ya, everybody thinks Danny is a jerk
其实他不是 那不过是种观点 带出的反向观点罢了
he's not really a jerk, it's just the theory generating its own anti-theory.
不管  我们俩 就我和丹尼
Anyway, there we were, it's me and Danny,
我在想 我这是在干嘛? 手里竟拿把剃刀
and I'm wondering what the hell am I doing with a razor in my hand
他说这是为了一部诺曼的电影
he says it's for a Norman Taurog picture
但朱蒂也在场 她认识诺曼
but Judy Canova is there and she knows Norman.
她说丹尼不是在拍诺曼的戏
She says, "Danny is not doing a Norman Taurog picture,
他只是要你帮他剃毛
he just wants you to shave his back."
获利的就是他
And that's who benefits.
"懒月亮" 霍比及惠特妮主演
HOBIE DOYLE "Lazy OL' MOON"
再另一个较有生气的地方
In livelier precincts, the swells of Dreamland
聚集了一群夜生活的人 检视着一块已然织成的丝娟柔纱
gather to inspect the completed weave of another piece of gossamer.
另一部电影 对终日辛劳的人类来说 不啻为一剂缓解痛苦的良药
Another movie, another portion of balm for the ache of a toiling mankind.
她在哪?   - 别发脾气 我在这呢
- Where is she? - Hold your horses, I'm right here.
你在想什么 卷毛的?
What's on your mind, Curly?
我把那块派从窗台拿走 其实不能怪我
Not my fault you saw me take that pie off the sill,
不怪你? 那怪谁  卷毛的?
Not your fault? Who's fault was it, Curly?
要怪喔...都怪那懒月亮!
Why that... crazy lazy full moon!
要是早两星期 你就看不到我偷派了
2 weeks ago, you'd never see me take it.
该死的月亮 有啥屁用
Darn you, moon. What good are you anyway.
我还不知道有这段 唱歌这场戏他们要我一次过
Don't know about this part, they only gave me one shot at the song.
真希望没有月亮
I wished there never was no moon.
也希望没有霸道的老女人
I wished there weren't no bossy ol' women.
别怪月亮 卷毛 它只会发亮
Don't blame that moon, Curly. She can't do nothing but shine.
懒月亮 一直亮着
Lazy ol' moon keep shining.
可恶
Darn you.
你再也没机会
You turn Curly Stirling in to the authorities
举发我卷毛啦
for the last time.
懒月亮 一直亮着
Lazy ol' moon keep shining.
一如往常
pining just to be
在那古老的农场
On that old plantation,
我曾漫步游荡
where I used to roam
照亮疲惫的我的归途
Light my weary way back home.
可恶 它去哪了?
Darn, where'd she go?
懒月亮 一直亮着
Lazy Old Moon keep shining,
月光洒在我身
shining down for me
在城市的另一角 另一组角色正要上演
Another part of town, another cast of characters.
艾迪要执行另一个任务
Another task, for Eddie Mannix.
约瑟夫 公证人事务所
JOSEPH SILVERMAN SURETIES BONDS . ESCROW
...丑闻没爆出前就解决掉...
... done before, which is not to say they were...
我们刚要为狄安娜解释
Ah, we're just getting started, I've been taking DeeAnna through this.
约瑟夫曾...
So Joseph has done...
帮我们干过不少好事
well, just a whole lot of good work for us in the past
只要我们需要公证人或者第三者
Whenever we've needed a witness or a third party for,
或者...陈述委屈及离间感情
I don't know, a petition of grievance or alienation of affection.
他可靠吗?    - 我是有担保的 小姐
- And he's reliable? - I'm bonded, miss.
约瑟夫是我们所知地球上最可靠的人
Joseph Silverman is the most reliable human being on the planet, in our experience.
那次克雷格酒驾撞到人
When Chubby Cregar was intoxicated and hit that pedestrian on Gower,
我们立马把车转到约瑟夫名下
we had that vehicle title transferred to Joe's name
让约瑟夫关了六个月
and Joe did 6 months in LA County lock-up.
你现在没喝酒了吧?
But you're off the sauce now?
I never touch it. It was a legal 铿ction.
从不喝酒 那只是法律上作假
没错
That's right.
每当公司需要某个符合法律标准的...
When the studio needs someone who meets the legal standard of...
希德 该怎么说呢      - "那个人"
- how did you put it, Sid? - Personhood.
约瑟夫就会挺身而出扮演"那个人"
Joe steps in and acts as the, uh. . . person.
那你是专业的..."那个人"?
So you're a professional. . . person?
没错  小姐 请在这和这签名
That's right, miss. Initial here, and here.
约瑟夫当养父直到你领养
Joe will be the foster parent until such time as
他一取得抚养权 你就马上可以申请领养
you adopt the child, which you can do as soon as Joe takes possession of it,
他可靠吗?   - 小姐 我是有担保的
- And he's reliable? - I'm bonded, miss.
你所签的文件不会公开
The release papers you're signing will not be a matter of public record.
所有文件会封存到2015年
all these documents will be sealed, until the year 2015.
谁也别耍小聪明    - 谁也别耍小聪明
- And no one's the wiser. - No one the wiser
没影迷 没媒体 没开庭
No fans. No press. No court officials.
甚至没公证人   - 约瑟夫自己就是
- Not even a notary public. - Joe himself is the notary.
你的手臂一定超壮的
You must have very strong forearms.
需要很多力气去压这个印监吧?
Is it hard, squeezing it like that?
这是我的工作 小姐
It's part of the job, miss.
曼尼斯先生 要通霄吗?    - 我们俩都要
- Late night, Mr. Mannix? - A late night for both of us.
Will you call Projection 7 and have them lace up yesterday's dailies on Hail, Caesar!?
打给七号影棚把"凯萨万岁"昨天拍的底片送来
好的 昨天的吗?
Sure thing. Yesterdays
谢谢 史考第
Thanks, Scotty.
罗马人先于奴隶!
Roman before slaves!
让开!猪头!
Make room! You fools!
罗马人先于奴隶!
Roman before slaves!
让开!
Make room!
怎样  可以吗?    - 卡!
- How's that, what'd you think? - Cut!
- Hail Caesar, 27 Baker Two.? - Action!
"凯萨万岁"第27幕第二遍   - 开拍!
说吧 我听着
Go ahead, I'm listening.
瓦特跟那临时演员谈过了 正是他
Walt talked to the extra, right guy,
但他不知道败德被带去哪
no info,  doesn't know where they took Baird,
但他描述了载他走的那辆卡车
but described the truck they put him in.
卡!
Cut!
瓦特找到那辆车的车主 正在跟他谈
Walt found the guy who owns the truck and is talking to him.
第四遍
Baker 4.
瓦特总是能解决麻烦 真棒    - 开拍!
- Walt's a problem-solver, he's a good man. - Action!
还有吗?
What else?
公关部刚刚送来霍比的首映报告 还不错
PR just called in their report on Hobie Doyle premier: Warm reception.
我嘴里有东西
I felt something like I had some spittle.
第六遍    - 开拍!
- Baker 6. - Action!
好吧  他很棒
Okay, he's terrific.
斜视! 斜视那庄严的形象
Squint! Squint against the grandeur.
有点刺眼  刺眼啦!
He's blinding, blinding!
好 我们看看这做啥用的
Right. Let's see what we can do here.
好啦
Okay.
尺寸虽不对 但可用上
Well, I don't think it's regulation size but, it'll have to do.
听说过日本摺纸吗?
You ever hear of origami the Japanese do?
Uh-huh.
这是义大利摺纸    - 是喔
- This here is Italian origami. - Yeah.
看到没 就酱...
See. Now, you just...
再看看能做什么
Let's see how she does now.
喔 它正偷偷向后看呢
Oh, she's peeking back.
它跑了
Hoh, there she goes.
喔 它在大叫
Oh, she's bawling.
搞定!
Clear!
这就是为什么我从点义大利面
This is why I never order it with meat sauce.
霍比 你是怎么开始演电影的?    - 被绳子绑来的
- How'd you get into pictures, Hobie? - Got roped into it.
够啦
Stop.
别再...玩...你的...食物啦
Stop... playing... with your... food.
那是吃的!
food!
是你在玩    - 别闹了
- You're the one playing with it. - Stop it.
我刚开始演骑马的
Pictures. Well, I wrangled for a while
后来他们发现我还会说几句台词
and then they saw I could say a line or two.
当当路人甲或警官
and I was Bad Clem or Deppity Number Two
或替身几年 然后有人听到我唱歌
or the guy's buddy for a couple of years and then someone heard me singing,
就让我出名啦
they made me the guy.
你太可爱了
You're awfully cute.
这算什么
Aw heck, you ain't seen the half of it
让你看看什么叫可爱
I'll show you cute, just a second here a little.
马上让你看看演牛仔的纪念品
souvenir from my rode days.
是这样的 那是我正在套牛
Tell ya what, I was steer busting
我向下 牛向上
and I went down, the steer went up,
我的牙就全飞去德州了
and my teeth headed off for east Texas.
等等 马上又回来了
Here, it's coming round again.
你给的少     - 就得的少
- You got to give a little. - Take a little.
心就少伤点
- And let your poor heart break a little - And let your poor heart break a little
那就是故事说得 那就是爱的光辉
That's the story of, that's the glory of love
(用我腰带绑着的箱子...赎金)
(Attache case with my belt... Ransom money)
少笑点 就少哭点
You've got to laugh a little, cry a little,
让云轻轻飘过...
let the clouds roll by a...
真有趣啊(这是特色莉)
(Thessaly Thacker) Well now, this is interesting.
我还不知道你们俩是朋友
(Thessaly Thacker) I didn't know you two were friends.
Aw heck yeah, we-we just caught my picture, Lazy Ol' Moon?
我们刚去看了我的"懒月亮"
我想我们是...
And I guess we're...
没错我们是朋友..我们是...
Yes, we're friends, we're...
Well, we're 铿xing to be friendly, tell you that.
正在发展友谊
That's good: Fixing to be Friendly? That can be my column headline.
好啊: “发展友谊”就是专栏标题啦
我认为没问题    - 祝你们玩得愉快
- Well, I guess that'd be okay. - Have a good evening.
我提到电影名 或许这样做没错
I mentioned the name of my picture, I think we're supposed to do that.
真有趣啊(这是朵拉)
(Thora) Well now, this is interesting.
我还以为我会拿到独家
(Thora): I thought I was getting an exclusive on this.
我要知道到底是怎么一回事
I'd like to know what the hell is going on here.
Well, like I said, we just saw Lazy Ol' Moon? and...
我刚说了 我们一起看"懒月亮"...
And Hobie and I are 铿xing to be friendly.
霍比和我正在发展友谊
虾米?
WHAT?
我们正...    - 得了吧
- We're just... - (Thora): Friends, my foot.
霍比 怎么了?
What's the matter, Hobie?
我得走了  抱歉
- I got to skedaddle, so sorry. - Oh.
我一定要看看你演的 我期待着
I had to catch one of your pictures next time, I'm looking forward to it.
再见 霍比
Goodbye, Hobie.
嘿 钥匙给我 我要开了
Hey, toss me them keys, pard. I'm taking the car.
洛克希德公司
LOCKHEED INTERNATIONAL AIRCRAFT
霍比 你也是共产党吗?
Hobie Doyle. You're a communist too?
原来是共产党干的?
So it's commies?
你来过吗?
You ever been in this place?
很棒吧? 这里是伯特的!
Pretty nice, huh? It's Burt Gurney's!
他会唱会跳 真有品味
He sings, he dances. He's got taste.
你一个人吗?
You here alone?
其他人都去海滩了
Everyone else went down to the beach.
那好 老兄
Well, all right, pard.
我们回市里去吧 你可把曼尼斯先生急坏了
Let's us head on back to town. You got Mr. Mannix worried sick.
减速
Easy.
就这
Here.
照顾好它
Take care of him.
跟他讲     - 快给他.
- Tell him. - Give it to him.
同志 同志!
Comrade! Comrade!
向你致敬
We salute you.
你要去莫斯科 当苏联人
You are going to Moscow to become Soviet Man.
参与创造未来
and help forge the future.
我们留在这 继续潜伏 伪装资本家的佣人
We stay behind, continuing to serve in our disguise as capitalist handmaiden.
但 这些钱该献给事业 而不是我们这些仆人
But, the money should go to the cause not to the servant of the cause.
没错!    - 没错
- Yes! - That's right.
这个...
We... Well...
是我们对共产党的微薄贡献
Our modest contribution to the Comintern.
他们会很高兴的
They will be pleased.
不!
No! No!
恩格斯!
Eng...! Engels!
- Oh. - Oh...
Oh, oh, no...
你为什么要这样?
Why did you do that? Why did you do that?
Hoh.
天啊 这么晚了 我麻烦大了
Oh, boy, it's late. I am in the doghouse.
别载我去家里 去比佛利山酒店
Better forget about my place. Drop me off at the Beverly Hills Hotel.
好吧
Alright then.
Huh!
你哪位?    - 陶德
- Who're you? - Todd.
陶德...
Todd...
你订的早餐是热的还盒装的?
You have a hot breakfast or a box breakfast?
我...哪知啊
I... I don't know.
你是基本演员还是临时演员?
Are you a principal or an extra?
应该是基本演员吧
I think I'm a principal.
好
Yeah.
我在想"到底怎么回事!"
I'm thinking, "What the hell!"
我也曾在陌生的房间里醒来
I've woken up in strange houses before but never without a broad next to me.
但身边至少会有个女人
- Uh-huh. - These guys were pretty interesting, though.
They've actually 铿gured out the laws that dictate... everything.
这些人挺有趣的 他们发现了支配一切的...规律
历史 社会学 政治学 道德 等等一切
History, sociology, politics, morality. Everything.
都写在"资本论"里
It's all in a book called "Kapital", with a K.
是吗?   - 是喔
- That right? - Yeah.
你绝不会相信的
You're not gonna believe this,
他们甚至弄明白电影公司在干什么
these guys even figured it out what's going on here at the studio.
这只不过是资本主义的一个工具
Because the studio is nothing more than an instrument of capitalism.
是的 我们盲目遵循这些规律 就像其他机构一样
Yes, so we blindly follows these laws like any other institution.
The laws these guys've 铿gured out.
他们却发现这些规律
电影公司用电影服务这系统
The studio makes pictures to serve the system,
这就是它的功能 就是我们所做的
that's it's function, that's really what we're all up to, here.
- Is it? - Yeah, we're just con铿rming
是吗?    - 是 我们只不过是在证实
what they call the status quo.?
他们所谓的"现实"的东西
I mean, we might tell ourselves that we're creating?something of artistic value,
我是说 也许会跟自己说我们正在"创造"艺术价值
或者还会说...电影事业是有精神层面的
that there's some sort of spiritual dimension to the picture business,
但实际不过是只纽约的肥猫
but what it is, is this fat cat,
远在纽约的深刻先生经营着这家公司
Nick Schenk, out in New York running this factory
然后略施小惠...
that's serving up these lollypops to the...
你们叫它是棒棒糖...
what did you use to call the a brand circuses for the...
什么? 别...
What? Wait...
给我听好 混球
Now, you listen to me, buster.
深刻先生和这家公司待你不薄
Nick Schenk and this studio have been good to you
对其它在此工作的人都很好
and to everyone else who works here.
如果你再说深刻先生坏话
If I ever hear you bad mouthing Mr. Schenk again
我就送你去坐牢
it'll be the last thing you say before I have you tossed into jail
你再好好说去
for colluding in your own abduction.
艾迪 我不会那样
Eddie! I wouldn't, I would never do that.
闭嘴
Shut up.
快滚出去 把"凯萨万岁!"演完
You're going to go out there and you're going to finish "Hail, Caesar!"
你要把那段话说完
You're gonna give the speech at the feet of the penitent thief
而且要字字相信
and you're gonna believe every word you say.
你是个演员 你就是吃这行饭的
You're gonna do it because you're an actor and that's what you do.
就像那些导演
Just like the director does what he does,
编剧 场记 打版的
and the writer and the script girl and the guy who claps the slate.
你必须去做 因为这部戏有价值
You're gonna do it because the picture has Worth
为本片服务 你就有价值 这点可别忘了
and you have Worth if you serve the picture and you're never gonna forget that again.
好好 艾迪
Okay, Eddie, okay.
我不会忘了 艾迪
I won't forget it, Eddie.
最好别忘了
You're damn right you won't.
只要我还当位
Not as long as I run this dump.
败德
Baird.
做好你的明星!
Go out there and be a star!
曼尼斯先生!
Mr. Mannix!
既然你要上车了 就把花拿去吧
Since you're going to your car, I thought you might want to take this.
这是什么?    - 狄安娜送的
- What is it? - From DeeAnna Moran.
为了谢谢你 她不用领养自己的孩子了
Thank you, and she doesn't need to adopt her baby after all.
Huh!
她昨晚请约瑟夫吃饭 看来是聊得不错
She asked Joe Silverman out for dinner last night,
然后开车去棕榈泉
and I guess it went well, they drove to Palm Springs
今天一早三点结婚了
and were married at three this morning.
Huh.
会去很久吗? 今天行程
Will you be gone long? Today's call list.
不 不到一小时就回来 有私事要办
No, less than an hour, personal errand.
这束花配得不错
- Ah. - It's a nice arrangement.
她把帐记在公司头上了   - 是喔
- She charged it to the studio. - Right.
刚好要找你(这是朵拉)    - 早啊
- (Thora): Just coming to see you. - Good morning.
昨晚很抱歉 朵拉
Sorry about last night, Thora,
我不知你姊会来
I didn't know your sister would show up.
也许是这样 但我不经一事 不长一智
Well that's as may be, but I certainly learned my lesson.
艾迪 今天不管你说什么
Whatever you say today, Eddie Mannix,
明天我还是要登...
my column tomorrow is about...
On Wings as Eagles.?
“长翅如鹰”
朵拉 我建议你还是别写    - 我就知道你会这样说
- Thora, I wouldn't do that if I were you. - I'm sure you wouldn't.
不 不 你还不知道 我们坐下说
No, no, no, you don't understand. Let's sit down.
我要你别登是为你好
I'm telling you not to run the column, Thora, for your own good.
我自己知道谁好谁坏
I can judge my own interest.
这会是年度最佳报导
This will be the story of the year
赫斯报业集团正再重振好莱坞专栏
And it so happens, the Hearst Syndicate is looking to pick up a Hollywood column.
你认为这是轻而易举的?    - 当然
- And you think this'll cinch it for you. - You know it will.
败德是你们最有名的明星
Baird Whitlock, your biggest star,
got his 铿rst major part in On Wings as Eagles?
在"长翅如鹰"一片中担当第一主角
靠的是与该片导演搞同性恋
by engaging in sodomy
就是那位罗伦斯罗伦兹
with the picture's director, Laurence Laurentz.
这个我们都知道了
We've all heard the story.
但有件事你没听过
But here's something you haven't heard:
你消息来源是个共产党
your source is a communist.
如果你报了就会被抓
If you print it it'll be dismissed as a commie smear tactic
你也会被当作共产党帮凶被解雇
and you'll be dismissed as a commie stooge.
伯特已经离开这国家 他所属的集团
Burt Gurney has left the country, the cell he was part of
也被警方捣毁
has been smashed by the police.
或许你认为他可信 因为他是劳伦兹先生的现任...宠儿
You might've thought he was credible because he's Mr. Laurentz's current... protege,
但你不想被当作伯特的喉舌吧?
but, you don't want to be seen as Burt Gurney's mouthpiece after this.
你怎么知道伯特是我的消息来源?
How did you know Burt was my source?
昨天深夜跟罗伦斯谈过 得出这样推论
Late last night, I talked to Laurence, put two and two together.
既然碰到你了 我就不必给你送去了
Well, no reason to send this since I ran into you.
这是为昨晚特色莉不请自来表示歉意
It's by way of apology for Thessaly homing in last night.
我很看重我们的友谊 朵拉
I do value our friendship, Thora.
我还有要事 快迟到了
And I'm late for something important.
为何向这个希伯来人下跪 喔脱落糗死?
Why on your knees before this Hebrew, Autolochus?
我昨天遇见过他 格拉古
I encountered him before, Gracchus,
就在去约沙法的井边
beside the well of Jehosaphat.
举止多高贵的人啊
And what manner of man.
他是以色列人的祭司 却被其他祭司所不容
He is a priest of the Israelites, despised even by the other priests.
不  在昨的行军中
No. On yesterday's march,
一路上的风尘让我困顿
punished by the dust of the road,
I sought to drink 铿rst at the well,
我抢着要头一个喝到井水
而我所管的那些奴隶们干渴远甚于我
before the slaves and my charge who's thirst was far greater than my own.
本来就罗马人先于奴隶
A Roman drinks before a slave.
这个人给所有人水喝
This man was giving water to all.
他眼中没有罗马人和奴隶
He saw no Roman and he saw no slave.
只有人
He saw only men.
虚弱的人 他给予救助
Weak men and gave suckle.
遭受痛苦的 他给予安慰
He saw suffering which he sought to ease.
对罪人 他却给予爱
He saw sin and gave love.
爱吗 喔脱落糗死?
Love, Autolochus?
他看到了我的罪和贪婪 格拉古
He saw my own sin, Gracchus, and greed.
但我在眼中却没看到责备
But in his eyes, I saw no shadow of reproach.
我只看到光明
I saw only light.
上帝之光
The light of god.
你是说众神之光
You mean, of the gods.
不是 格拉古 我的朋友
I do not, friend Gracchus.
这是希伯来人 是唯一上帝的儿子
This Hebrew is a son of the one God,
the God of this far-铿ung tribe.
就是偏远部族的神
神的受膏者 为何就不能出现在这
Why shouldn't God's anointed appear here,
出现在这些怪人当中 来担当他们的罪?
among these strange people to shoulder their sins.
在这里 格拉古
Here, Gracchus.
在这片骄阳灼烤的土地上
In this, sun-drenched land.
他为什么就选这个样
Why should he not take this form.
以个普通人的样
The form of an ordinary man.
他不仅为我们带来古老的真理
A man bringing us not the old truths.
还有新的
but a new one.
新的真理
A new truth.
A truth beyond the truth that we can see.就是那高于我们眼所能见的真理
A truth beyond the truth that we can see.
A truth beyond this world.高于这世界的真理
A truth beyond this world.
A truth told not in words but in light.不是用言语而是用光明来宣示的真理
A truth told not in words but in light.
A truth that we could see if we have but这个真理我们能看到 只要我们有...
A truth that we could see if we have but...
只要我们有...
if we have but...
卡 卡!
Cut. Cut!
信德   只要有信德
Faith. Have but faith.
信德
Faith.
信德! 信德! 可恶!    - 再来一遍
- Faith! Faith! God damn it! - Roll it again.
原来不是...    - 改啦
- Is it the... - They changed it.
你记住大部分啦 不错啦
You got most of it, man. You're alright.
好吧 等一下
Alright, hang on.
能帮我擦擦汗吗 我一身汗了
Could I get a pat down, I'm sweating like a pig in this thing.
啊 去你的鸟蛋!
Ah, son of a bitch!
请神父降福我 准我罪人告解
Bless me Father, for I have sinned.
你多久没来告解了 孩子啊?
How long since your last confession, my son?
27小时前
It's been... 27 hours.
不用那么快 孩子
It's really too often, my son.
你没那么坏    - 神父 我不知道
- You're not that bad - I don't know, father.
我又偷抽了一根还是两根烟
I snuck a cigarette or two.
没准时回家吃晚餐
I didn't make it home in time for dinner.
我还...
And I...
发怒 打了一个影星
I struck a movie star in anger.
好吧 念五遍万福玛丽亚
All right. Five Hail Marys.
好
Okay.
神父
Father.
怎么啦 孩子?
Yes, my son?
神父 可以问个事吗?
May I ask you something, father.
当然可以 孩子
Of course, my son.
是不是轻而易举的事
If there's something that's easy.
就是...错的?
Is that... wrong?
轻而易举?    - 容易做的事
- Easy? - Uh... easy to do.
轻而易举...
Easy to...
例如轻松的活
Like an easy job.
也不是干坏事
No, it's not a bad job, it's not bad.
但...而是...
But... then...
有另一份工作
There's this other job.
不是那么容易
That's... It's not so easy.
其实是很困难的事...
In fact, it's hard. It's...
It's so hard, Father, sometimes I don't know if I can keep doing it.非常困难 神父 我也不知道能否坚做持下去
It's so hard, Father, sometimes I don't know if I can keep doing it.
但它..它...
But, it... it...
但看起来比较对
But it seems right.
我不知怎么解释
I don't know how to explain.
上帝要我们做对的事
God wants us to do what's right.
是
Yeah.
是 当然是
Yeah, course He does.
那个告诉你什么是对的声音...
The inner voice that tells you what's right,
来自上帝  孩子
it comes from God, my son.
我明白了    - 这就是k的方式...
- Yeah, got it. - That's His way of saying that...
对 对 我明白了  谢谢
Yeah, yeah, I got it. Thanks.
新墨西哥的雨还在下
Still raining in Gallup, New Mexico
and the Tucumcari?crew has shot all the plates we need for Came the Rain.?
图库姆卡里拍摄组已经拍好"雨来罗"
在现在的天气下把高潮戏拍出 我们来重新为这部片命名
Well, just shoot the showdown in the weather and we'll retitle it.
"Tucumcari tempest". Desert Squall? Hold Back the Storm?
"图库姆卡里暴风雨""沙漠狂飙""挡住风暴"
风波乍起 又归平静
The stories begin. The stories end.
我也不知道 发回给编剧改吧
I don't know, bounce it off the writers.
就酱
So, it is be.
这是今天要打的电话
Here's today's call list.
加上一个 打给洛克希德的卡西达先生
Add a call to a Mr. Cuddahy at the Lockheed Corporation.
长话短话?
Long call, short?
Thanks but no thanks? how long was that?
'多谢盛情 恕难接受" 这算长还短?
但艾迪的故事...    - 先打给谁?
- But the story of Eddie Mannix... - Who do we call first?
... 永远不会结束
... will never end.
New York 铿rst. Time to check in with Mr. Schenk.
先打纽约 该和深刻先生联络了
因为他的故事 都是由那永恒之光写成的
For his is a tale written in light everlasting.
片头待补
神灵异相待补
我对你的热情... (明星在我们手上 准备十万 听候指示)